<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<feed>
<entry>
<id>OhctMXlW0PM</id>
<title><![CDATA[Magical Weight Gain | Marathi | Quizzical Problem]]></title>
<duration>2:43</duration>
<date>2015-03-06</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is an amazing trick you can perform and impress your friends. It's almost magical and counter-intuitive and you can also learn principle of flotation, sinking and buoyancy. For this...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>C2g5SuIFNoM</id>
<title><![CDATA[Magnetic Propeller | Marathi | Fun with Magnets]]></title>
<duration>2:41</duration>
<date>2015-03-05</date>
<description><![CDATA[This magnetic propeller spins as you blow. The pen in the middle keeps standing and does not fall. Why? To understand this, let's make a model. You will need 4 ring magnets, wooden rods,...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>tkNIvURJ2as</id>
<title><![CDATA[Fun with Boyle's Law | Marathi | With with Pressure]]></title>
<duration>3:29</duration>
<date>2015-03-02</date>
<description><![CDATA[In this experiment we will have lots of fun with several variations of Boyle's Law. We need 4 big and brand new 60-ml syringes and a few balloons. Fill a small amount of water in a balloon...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>hnngp6ccOA4</id>
<title><![CDATA[Spin Fan, Light LED | Marathi | Fun with Electricity]]></title>
<duration>0:59</duration>
<date>2015-03-02</date>
<description><![CDATA[Salvage a used Cooling Fan from an old Computer and attach an LED to the two leads of the fan motor. Blow hard to make the fan spin. The motor will produce a current and light the LED.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>cclDQOxNRy8</id>
<title><![CDATA[Shirt with Tie | Marathi | Wonderful Origami]]></title>
<duration>2:55</duration>
<date>2015-03-02</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make a Shirt and Tie by Paper Folding!]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>_vrwil0IpR4</id>
<title><![CDATA[Magical Floating Pen | Marathi | Fun with Magnets]]></title>
<duration>2:48</duration>
<date>2015-02-24</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make this amazing toy– the Magical pen stand. After finishing work you can just leave the pen in there and it will remain vertical. The pen will not fall down. You will need an old CD, some...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>KShlL4hhhSY</id>
<title><![CDATA[Soap Films | Marathi]]></title>
<duration>3:10</duration>
<date>2015-02-24</date>
<description><![CDATA[Everyone has played with soap bubbles but today we will make different shapes with soap films. These films have a very interesting and unique property of minimum surface area. Soap surface...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>_aqCevnI6bk</id>
<title><![CDATA[Knotted String | Marathi | Fun with a String]]></title>
<duration>2:35</duration>
<date>2015-02-24</date>
<description><![CDATA[This wonderful string game enables you to tie many equally placed knots in a string in one simple jerk. This is a story about a farmer who wants to divide his land in five equal parts so that...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>jWQQXmjIqsk</id>
<title><![CDATA[Magical Floating Propeller | Marathi | Fun with Magnets]]></title>
<duration>2:10</duration>
<date>2015-02-24</date>
<description><![CDATA[This levitating toy can be made at home. You need a bottle propeller, an old bottle, a stiff straw and ring magnets this toy uses the principle that magnets with same pole will repel. If you...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>fd84GcLwrtc</id>
<title><![CDATA[Simple Strobe | Marathi]]></title>
<duration>3:14</duration>
<date>2015-02-13</date>
<description><![CDATA[Used batteries are a big environmental menace but today we will discarded batteries we can make a very simple strobe. And coincidentally you will see the logo of nuclear radiation warning....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>eFiW9HNyWww</id>
<title><![CDATA[Shell Sack | Marathi]]></title>
<duration>2:59</duration>
<date>2015-02-13</date>
<description><![CDATA[We see a lot of pips and peels of eatables around our roads and this simple and ingenious toy can help making our surrounding clean. With just an A-paper and a tape we can make a sack to hold...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>S-DAjjEPWpU</id>
<title><![CDATA[Christmas Tree | Marathi | Modular Origami]]></title>
<duration>2:24</duration>
<date>2015-02-04</date>
<description><![CDATA[Let's celebrate Christmas by making this wonderful Tree out of paper. Every year we cut around 80million trees worldwide. These trees are traditionally spruce, pine or fir have needle like...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>bdY9qphCCm0</id>
<title><![CDATA[Falling Chain | Marathi | Spectacular Experiment]]></title>
<duration>1:38</duration>
<date>2015-02-04</date>
<description><![CDATA[This falling chain graphically demonstrates basic laws of Physics. Falling beads of the chain do not touch the glass instead jump in the air and make a wonderful loop. To perform this you need...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>qKF9-n_E2GE</id>
<title><![CDATA[Along the Grain | Marathi | Fun with Newspapers]]></title>
<duration>2:03</duration>
<date>2015-02-04</date>
<description><![CDATA[In this experiment the girl is tearing a newspaper ALONG its grain and she is able to tear fairly long and parallel strips. On the other hand the boy is tearing the newspaper ACROSS the grain...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>J806nU0lupk</id>
<title><![CDATA[Hot Air Balloon | Marathi | Flies High!]]></title>
<duration>1:17</duration>
<date>2015-02-04</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is a beautiful model of a readymade Hot Air Balloon. This Hot Air Balloon is made of strong kite paper. You can see there is a frame – a ring of thin wire. There are cross-wires attached...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>rHwTHRwARN0</id>
<title><![CDATA[Area Unchanged | Marathi | Fun with Maths]]></title>
<duration>2:44</duration>
<date>2015-02-04</date>
<description><![CDATA[In this experiment we will explore the area of triangles. You will need pencils of various lengths and two scales. Look at the two triangles – one to the left and right. They look very different...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>D7tS5XmgzVk</id>
<title><![CDATA[Tree Tale Kadamba | Marathi | Tree Tale]]></title>
<duration>2:11</duration>
<date>2015-02-04</date>
<description><![CDATA[Well we are sitting in the parking lot of Akashganga in IUCAA, Pune. IUCAA is the astronomy research institute based in the Pune University. We are sitting below a very important tree. In Hindi...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>89L6agURoBc</id>
<title><![CDATA[Orange Lamp | Marathi |]]></title>
<duration>2:51</duration>
<date>2015-01-30</date>
<description><![CDATA[We are going to make a very beautiful lamp from an orange. Yes, an orange! You will need an orange, sweet lime, cutter, some wax jelly and a wick. Cut the top of the orange with a knife and...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>9upqux3IH2A</id>
<title><![CDATA[Cubical Lantern | Marathi |]]></title>
<duration>3:49</duration>
<date>2015-01-30</date>
<description><![CDATA[We are going to make a beautiful lantern. Take a printout on a stiff A-4 card sheet. First cut all along the outline. This is the shape you will get. Now score all the lines with the help of...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>gX8h1bYPz1Q</id>
<title><![CDATA[Join the Circles | Marathi | Simple, Wonderful Jigsaw]]></title>
<duration>1:47</duration>
<date>2015-01-30</date>
<description><![CDATA[This beautiful matching puzzle has been inspired by the Sri Aurobindo Ashram, Puduchery. Take printouts of two exactly similar patterns on stiff card sheets – one blue and the other red....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>YbeEeLabXwE</id>
<title><![CDATA[E-Motional Cup | Marathi | Fun with Paper Cups]]></title>
<duration>2:13</duration>
<date>2015-01-30</date>
<description><![CDATA[This cup in motion shows all the different emotions of a boy and a girl. And the best part is that you can utilize the paper cups that we as a society trash in plenty every day. First take...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>4FdCfXOtUSo</id>
<title><![CDATA[Magnetic Top | Marathi | Brilliant Magnetic Toy]]></title>
<duration>3:17</duration>
<date>2015-01-30</date>
<description><![CDATA[This magnetic top spins and follows a curvy path along the aluminum sheet. How to make this magnetic top? You will need a plastic ball, steel wire, aluminum sheet, magnet, spoke and glue. The...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>b7KwrglcbMI</id>
<title><![CDATA[Blooming Lotus | Marathi |]]></title>
<duration>4:46</duration>
<date>2015-01-30</date>
<description><![CDATA[This blooming lotus looks very pretty in the dark. You will love the play of shadows and light. For making this model you will require a total of 12 strips of paper 30-cm long and 1-cm wide....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>XDUdHqL68yc</id>
<title><![CDATA[Pop-Up Hummingbird | Marathi | 3-Card]]></title>
<duration>2:02</duration>
<date>2015-01-20</date>
<description><![CDATA[Today we will make a beautiful Pop-Up card of a Humming Bird. This pop card of the Hummingbird looks extremely elegant. First you need to take a printout of the Humming Birds on a stiff card...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>MOmw5pOQ2xs</id>
<title><![CDATA[No Knot Air Balloon | Marathi |]]></title>
<duration>2:07</duration>
<date>2015-01-20</date>
<description><![CDATA[We are going to see a very clever method of tying an inflated balloon without a knot. You need a stiff card piece 5-cm square and a piece of thread. Normally after inflating a balloon you tie...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>hpobtU7-TPY</id>
<title><![CDATA[Opening Up | Marathi |]]></title>
<duration>3:27</duration>
<date>2015-01-20</date>
<description><![CDATA[In this delightful experiment a close fist cut out from newsprint is placed in water. And slowly the fingers open up! How does this happen? For this you require cutouts of various shapes –...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>9J1xtRhvexE</id>
<title><![CDATA[Pluck and Spin | Marathi |]]></title>
<duration>1:20</duration>
<date>2015-01-20</date>
<description><![CDATA[For this experiment you need an aluminum chain and some color fans. Place one propeller in the chain made of beads and pull both ends of the chain with a jerk. The fan will start spinning....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>sqXHwNnR5Nc</id>
<title><![CDATA[Tangram - Seven Pieces Many Faces | Marathi | Fun Puzzle]]></title>
<duration>2:35</duration>
<date>2015-01-20</date>
<description><![CDATA[The Tangram is an ancient Chinese puzzle – invented thousands of years ago. It is made by cutting seven pieces from a square. There are two big triangles, two small triangles, one intermediate...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>mNYTJE6da2c</id>
<title><![CDATA[Lifting Fan | Marathi |]]></title>
<duration>2:01</duration>
<date>2015-01-16</date>
<description><![CDATA[As you blow on the fan it spins and lifts a card below. Why does the card lift? The spinning fan creates a low-pressure zone below it and that lifts-up the card.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>I5oGCmjMMWo</id>
<title><![CDATA[Book Mark | Marathi |]]></title>
<duration>2:24</duration>
<date>2015-01-16</date>
<description><![CDATA[We will be folding a BOOK MARK using a square piece of paper. Take a 10-cm edge square. Fold a diagonal to make a big triangle. Fold this triangle into half to make a smaller triangle. Open...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>jYdTX12wuk0</id>
<title><![CDATA[Rectangle to Flower | Marathi |]]></title>
<duration>3:14</duration>
<date>2015-01-16</date>
<description><![CDATA[You can make a beautiful flower from a paper rectangle. Take a red paper rectangle 20-cm long and 10-cm wide. The length of the paper will be double that of the width. Fold the paper in half,...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>rm1w4iQTZsQ</id>
<title><![CDATA[Quick Addition | Marathi | Fun with Maths]]></title>
<duration>1:46</duration>
<date>2015-01-16</date>
<description><![CDATA[Fredrick Gauss -- on whom the 'Bell-shaped Gaussian Curve' is named, was a child prodigy. It is important in science and mathematics not to do things mechanically but to look at patterns. This...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>h0-2EYCMg30</id>
<title><![CDATA[Folding Paper Heart | Marathi | Fun Origami]]></title>
<duration>3:21</duration>
<date>2014-12-24</date>
<description><![CDATA[Today we are going to make an Origami heart. For this you first fold the square paper in half. Unfold and fold it in half the other way too. Then fold one edge to the mid-line. Upturn the paper...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>KTN7weV6v2c</id>
<title><![CDATA[Paper Balloon l Marathi]]></title>
<duration>4:04</duration>
<date>2014-12-23</date>
<description><![CDATA[I am going to show you how to make a paper balloon. First fold the paper diagonally. Then unfold and again fold the paper along its second diagonal. Then upturn the paper and fold a MINUS...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>R3oRP4Vmic0</id>
<title><![CDATA[Revolutionary Train | Marathi | Train in a Tunnel]]></title>
<duration>3:01</duration>
<date>2014-12-11</date>
<description><![CDATA[We are going to make a truly revolutionary train. As you place the two magnets and battery inside a bare copper coil the trains shoots like a bullet. You will need BARE Copper Wire, Strong...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>05fTW2xzM28</id>
<title><![CDATA[Who's Who at the Zoo | Marathi | Animal Jigsaw]]></title>
<duration>2:36</duration>
<date>2014-10-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is the most amazing puzzle. For children it is a delightful animal jigsaw. You can take a printout of this on a stiff card sheet from our website. Then color the animals and beautify them....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>8kUVd8_IqQ0</id>
<title><![CDATA[Diwali Lantern | Marathi | Don't curse Darkness, Light a Lamp!]]></title>
<duration>3:51</duration>
<date>2014-10-21</date>
<description><![CDATA[Diwali is the Festival of Lights in India. This is the time when millions of children make their own lanterns. This is the template on an A-4 size card sheet which can be downloaded from our...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>9WAYcEl3hVA</id>
<title><![CDATA[3-D  Pop Up House | Marathi |]]></title>
<duration>4:05</duration>
<date>2014-09-25</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make a 3-D replica of a nice cottage. You can send this 3-D Pop-Up card to your friends by post. We will need card sheet, paper to join the cardboard pieces, color pencils and lots of glue....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>BkZ4x3RioLI</id>
<title><![CDATA[Polythene Parachute | Marathi | Amazing Flier]]></title>
<duration>2:52</duration>
<date>2014-09-25</date>
<description><![CDATA[We all dream of having wings, flying and seeing the world from above. We can make a simple toy parachute and see it sailing down slowly when it's dropped from the roof. We will need a sheet...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>8-7Yrvrmwdg</id>
<title><![CDATA[Fire Tornado | Marathi | Fun with Heat]]></title>
<duration>2:55</duration>
<date>2014-09-24</date>
<description><![CDATA[For doing these spectacular fires show you will need ADULT HELP. You will need a circular wooden base, an old turntable, a metal bowl, cotton, wire mesh and kerosene. First you make a cylinder...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>NlVN2_edzdo</id>
<title><![CDATA[Levitating Candle | Marathi | Fun with Heat]]></title>
<duration>2:32</duration>
<date>2014-09-24</date>
<description><![CDATA[Wax candles are lighter than water so they float. But if we light a candle and enclose it in a container, then something very interesting happens. Now the candle floats up. You will need candles,...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>POoOGOI5ZeQ</id>
<title><![CDATA[Jumping Flame | Marathi | Fun with Heat]]></title>
<duration>2:16</duration>
<date>2014-09-24</date>
<description><![CDATA[Summers in India brings its own miseries - power cuts. So, during night time you might have to light a candle. What really burns in a candle? Is it the cotton wick, the wax or the gaseous...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>ZOxpxUfai90</id>
<title><![CDATA[Fluttering Twin Butterfly | Marathi | Flapping Butterfly]]></title>
<duration>4:11</duration>
<date>2014-09-24</date>
<description><![CDATA[Today is 12th June 2014 and it's a special day for us. We celebrate our 10th anniversary. Best wishes to everyone. This joyous fluttering butterfly is a perfect toy to make on this wonderful...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>5IMyPJPug-E</id>
<title><![CDATA[Smallest Burns Longest | Marathi | Fun with Heat]]></title>
<duration>3:14</duration>
<date>2014-09-24</date>
<description><![CDATA[Place three candles in a plate – tall, medium and small height. Light them and cover them with a jar. The tallest candle will extinguish first, followed by the middle on. The smallest will...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>3M7yNHV4ggA</id>
<title><![CDATA[Thirsty Bottle | Marathi | Fun with Heat]]></title>
<duration>2:32</duration>
<date>2014-09-24</date>
<description><![CDATA[It's the Indian summer. In the intense heat even our bottles turn thirsty and crave for water. In this experiment place a hot bottle upside down in a shallow plate of water. The bottle will...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>IUNc59jg7QA</id>
<title><![CDATA[Marble Swan | Marathi | Amazing Rolling Toy]]></title>
<duration>3:23</duration>
<date>2014-09-24</date>
<description><![CDATA[The marble swan is an amazingly creative toy. You will need a paper cup, a marble, glue, scissors and some sketch pens. First remove the circular base of the paper cup with the help of a paper...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>f-yYmrd07VA</id>
<title><![CDATA[Touchy Fountain | Marathi | Magical Fountain]]></title>
<duration>3:48</duration>
<date>2014-09-24</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is quite a Magical Fountain!]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>U6KVgU5rqwo</id>
<title><![CDATA[Perpetual Motion | Marathi | Amazing Machine]]></title>
<duration>2:50</duration>
<date>2014-09-24</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is not a perpetual motion machine – but a beautiful machine nonetheless. In this machine we provide the potential energy by placing marbles on top. The machine swivels – picks up a...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>57lzAj8d0Ak</id>
<title><![CDATA[3-D Kaleidoscope | Marathi | Fun with Light]]></title>
<duration>2:12</duration>
<date>2014-09-24</date>
<description><![CDATA[We have all seen a triangular kaleidoscope where one can see interesting patterns. With this toy you will enter an amazing magical room where you will see infinite reflections. All you will...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>r_y4en6oMFI</id>
<title><![CDATA[Tipsy Bottle | Marathi | Fun with Heat]]></title>
<duration>2:15</duration>
<date>2014-09-24</date>
<description><![CDATA[Sometimes people get drunk and can't walk straight. Here a bottle magically gets drunk on water and starts wobbling. Amazing experiment! You need a plastic bottle, cello tape and black paper....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>K-7Rkod0Hr4</id>
<title><![CDATA[Standing Paper Crane | Marathi | Elegant Sculptor]]></title>
<duration>2:39</duration>
<date>2014-09-23</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is a wonderful standing 3D paper crane you can make. You just need an A4 sheet of paper. Print it out from our website or from the link below this video. Fold it from the middle and cut...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>5ACp2s0frE8</id>
<title><![CDATA[Inflatable Lungs | Marathi | Biology in the Classroom]]></title>
<duration>3:24</duration>
<date>2014-09-23</date>
<description><![CDATA[Lungs are like 2 or 3 liter bags in side our bodies. We can make a working model of the lungs an old plastic bottle and some balloons. You will also have to improvise you make a Y-shaped, 3-way...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Hng5BKEBz4s</id>
<title><![CDATA[Radiometer | Marathi | Quizzing Apparatus]]></title>
<duration>2:51</duration>
<date>2014-09-23</date>
<description><![CDATA[Radiometer is a device which measures the intensity of electromagnetic radiation. The bulb radiometer was accidently invented by Mr. Crooke in 1873 while he was researching on the element Thallium ...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>NGKJbmnB2WI</id>
<title><![CDATA[Vacuum Lift | Marathi | Fun with Vacuum]]></title>
<duration>1:31</duration>
<date>2014-09-23</date>
<description><![CDATA[You can lift a glass by burning a piece of paper. You need a transparent glass, some water and a balloon. Take a thin walled glass which will not crack when a burnt paper is put inside it....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>YgUGNzkiCvg</id>
<title><![CDATA[Bird of Peace | Marathi | Amazing Paper Sculptor]]></title>
<duration>2:20</duration>
<date>2014-09-23</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is a wonderful symbol of peace, the dove. You can place this 3-D model on your work table or else gift it to your friends. First print it on a slightly hard paper. This stencil is available...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>yGWVLuz7d1I</id>
<title><![CDATA[Motor Pump | Marathi | Real Life Pump]]></title>
<duration>3:42</duration>
<date>2014-09-23</date>
<description><![CDATA[This wonderful pump is called as a Motor-Pump because it is operated by a small toy motor. You will need a toy motor, battery pack, a film can, flexi-pipes, double sided sticky tape etc. First...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>_AvfXyhEuC4</id>
<title><![CDATA[Add Water See Coin | Marathi | Fun with Light]]></title>
<duration>1:47</duration>
<date>2014-09-23</date>
<description><![CDATA[Is this a scientific illusion or magic a trick? You'll have to judge it for yourself. In this is wonderful experiment we can make a coin reappear. Place a bowl on a table. Place a coin in...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>x0N5HVrX4IA</id>
<title><![CDATA[Convection Smoke Flow | Marathi | Heat Currents]]></title>
<duration>2:09</duration>
<date>2014-09-23</date>
<description><![CDATA[This experiment is a very graphic demonstration of convection currents. You need a big cardboard box, transparency, candle and a few incense sticks. Make two holes in the side of a cardboard...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>1KB254ZPW6g</id>
<title><![CDATA[Paper Insect | Marathi | Fun with Paper]]></title>
<duration>2:30</duration>
<date>2014-09-23</date>
<description><![CDATA[Have you ever tried to catch a fly? It is hard because flies have an extremely sharp vision and a quick response. We will try and make a paper insect. What you need a card paper, scissors and...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>1-nUbazE2SM</id>
<title><![CDATA[Glass Lifts Glass | Marathi | Fun with Vacuum]]></title>
<duration>2:09</duration>
<date>2014-09-23</date>
<description><![CDATA[Please this activity under adult supervision. The science behind the experiment is simple. First burn a candle inside a glass to create a partial vacuum and then place another glass on top....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>jPCzTWMc898</id>
<title><![CDATA[Magical Coin | Marathi | Fun with Light]]></title>
<duration>2:17</duration>
<date>2014-09-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is the continuation of our disappearing coin trick. Here we will make the coin magically reappear. You will need a transparent glass, a coin and a water dropper. Place a coin underneath...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>161IzbAeySc</id>
<title><![CDATA[Disappearing Coin | Marathi | Fun with Light]]></title>
<duration>2:06</duration>
<date>2014-09-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[In this experiment we will make a coin disappear. For this simple trick you will need two transparent glasses and two coins. First place a coin on the table and place the first glass on its...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>8J5o3fou6tg</id>
<title><![CDATA[3-D Buddha | Marathi | Paper Sculptor]]></title>
<duration>3:14</duration>
<date>2014-09-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[5000 years back the Buddha wanted us to examine and question everything. This 3D greeting card is an inspiration for everyone. You need a simple A4 size paper printout of the Buddha's image....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>9OWR4j3oDUU</id>
<title><![CDATA[3-D Ganesha | Marathi | Paper Sculptor]]></title>
<duration>3:09</duration>
<date>2014-09-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[You can make this wonderful pop up of Ganesha with a square paper. Being a pop-up this card will also give you a 3D feel of Lord Ganesha. First, print out this picture from our website on a...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>92R0UMx5ACk</id>
<title><![CDATA[Tumbler | Marathi | Tumbling Toy]]></title>
<duration>3:13</duration>
<date>2014-09-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is a very joyous to play with. You need a card paper strip, a ping pong ball, a crazy ball and some cello tape. First take this ping pong ball and cut it into two equal halves. The way...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>BuWjcmUn2-A</id>
<title><![CDATA[Paper Deer | Marathi | Paper Sculptor]]></title>
<duration>3:49</duration>
<date>2014-09-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[You can fold this paper deer very easily and recreate a jungle at home. All you need is A4 size card paper. Fold the paper in the middle. You can actually print the whole outline of the deer...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>RwqSmUBUkHk</id>
<title><![CDATA[Violin Generator | Marathi | Fun with Electricity]]></title>
<duration>2:08</duration>
<date>2014-09-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[You can convert a simple toy motor into a generator by reversing the functionality of a motor. Apart from a toy motor you will need a pulley, two LEDs, spoke and bottle caps. Attach a pulley...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>zwAOltqwc5U</id>
<title><![CDATA[Oil Centrifuge | Marathi | Simple Centrifuge]]></title>
<duration>2:36</duration>
<date>2014-09-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[You can have much fun with stuff in your kitchen. To make this centrifuge you need colored water, cooking oil, bowl and some steel balls. First tape equal lengths of threads to the bowl and...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>xlKeByuytdQ</id>
<title><![CDATA[Fun with Water Lens | Marathi | Fun with Light]]></title>
<duration>1:55</duration>
<date>2014-09-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[You can make an amazing lens by filling a cylindrical glass with water. With this lens you can magically change the direction of the arrows. Take this piece of paper and draw two arrows on...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Y4dJa6TK9Gg</id>
<title><![CDATA[Circumference & Diameter Ratio - Pi | Marathi | Fun with Maths]]></title>
<duration>2:15</duration>
<date>2014-09-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[Using this simple and wonderful experiment you can see the approximate value of pi which is 22/7. You just need some plastic straws. You will need 29 equal size straws. With this experiment...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>oGTbxZa71oY</id>
<title><![CDATA[Soda Bottle Fountain | Marathi | Fun with Pressure]]></title>
<duration>1:52</duration>
<date>2014-09-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[You can make a wonderful fountain using the science behind high pressure and gases. You just need a chilled soda bottle from the fridge and brand new injection syringe. If you normally feel...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>HY0TlGeXsPM</id>
<title><![CDATA[Wireless Electricity Transmission | Marathi | Electromagnetism Alive!]]></title>
<duration>6:39</duration>
<date>2014-09-18</date>
<description><![CDATA[In this beautiful experiment we Transmit Electricity without wires. For this we need to make a small circuit. This project was made by several student of the New English School, Pune, India....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>fN5eTO--uFM</id>
<title><![CDATA[Solar Cap I Marathi I Cool cap!]]></title>
<duration>1:22</duration>
<date>2014-09-17</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is an indigenous product -- sold in the local market. In India the sun is so scorching that you need a cap to prevent your pate being burnt by the scorching sun. A small solar panel has...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>yIA21hVW4AM</id>
<title><![CDATA[Refractive Disappearance I Marathi I Its there and not there!]]></title>
<duration>3:08</duration>
<date>2014-09-17</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is an exciting experiment. Fill a dish with water. Place a glass lens in the water and you will be able to see it outline. However if you place the lens in cooking oil it seems to disappear....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>GIMxKz-tCmw</id>
<title><![CDATA[Flame in Water I Marathi I Magical Illumination]]></title>
<duration>2:04</duration>
<date>2014-09-17</date>
<description><![CDATA[Stand a sheet of clear glass on a table. Place a transparent plastic glass in front and fix a candle on the other side of the glass sheet. Now light the candle and pour water in the plastic...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>g8fQaiqETEQ</id>
<title><![CDATA[Reducing Boiling Point of Water I Marathi I Fun with pressure]]></title>
<duration>2:10</duration>
<date>2014-09-17</date>
<description><![CDATA[Boil some water in a Borosil flask and then shut its mouth tightly with a rubber cork. Hang the flask upside-down so that its large base is on top. Place a wet cloth on the base and pour cold...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>ZO7MWeZDH7s</id>
<title><![CDATA[Magnetic Oscillator | Marathi | Reciprocating Piston]]></title>
<duration>2:17</duration>
<date>2014-09-16</date>
<description><![CDATA[You will need a strong Neodymium Magnet, 400 turns insulated copper wire coil and an old plastic syringe, and a Nokia mobile charger. Wind the coil on the syringe and place loose the Neodymium...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>bfAGhnLDXfM</id>
<title><![CDATA[Oil Centrifuge | Marathi | Fun Centrifuge]]></title>
<duration>2:36</duration>
<date>2014-08-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[You can have much fun with stuff in your kitchen. To make this centrifuge you need colored water, cooking oil, bowl and some steel balls. First tape equal lengths of threads to the bowl and...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>f0oXA0ADOaU</id>
<title><![CDATA[Soda Bottle Fountain | Marathi | Fun Fountain]]></title>
<duration>1:52</duration>
<date>2014-08-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[You can make a wonderful fountain using the science behind high pressure and gases. You just need a chilled soda bottle from the fridge and brand new injection syringe. If you normally feel...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>f3ET_nNEa18</id>
<title><![CDATA[Violin Generator | Marathi | Amazing Generator]]></title>
<duration>2:08</duration>
<date>2014-08-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[You can convert a simple toy motor into a generator by reversing the functionality of a motor. Apart from a toy motor you will need a pulley, two LEDs, spoke and bottle caps. Attach a pulley...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>crAyIBdZYTs</id>
<title><![CDATA[Fun with Water Lens | Marathi | Fun with Light]]></title>
<duration>2:43</duration>
<date>2014-08-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[You can make an amazing lens by filling a cylindrical glass with water. With this lens you can magically change the direction of the arrows. Take this piece of paper and draw two arrows on...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>pgWKN5QOwJU</id>
<title><![CDATA[Tail of Pi | Marathi | Fun with 22/7]]></title>
<duration>2:34</duration>
<date>2014-08-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[Designed by Math enthusiast V. S. S. Sastry this long strip of flex-board depict the value of Pi to 1000 places. As flex-board is very durable it can easily be rolled up. Once this long placard...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>RJI9c0Cw_dU</id>
<title><![CDATA[Circumference and Diameter of Circle Pi | Marathi | Fun with Math]]></title>
<duration>2:15</duration>
<date>2014-08-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[Using this simple and wonderful experiment you can see the approximate value of pi which is 22/7. You just need some plastic straws. You will need 29 equal size straws. With this experiment...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>xxFYuRca3CA</id>
<title><![CDATA[STRAW TAPE DNA HELIX - MARATHI - Model of DNA!]]></title>
<duration>2:57</duration>
<date>2014-03-24</date>
<description><![CDATA[The DNA carries our inheritance code. It is a double helix made up of nucleotides. Each nucleotide contains sugar, phosphate and nitrogenous bases. The four nitrogenous bases are Adenine, Guanine ...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>jatX8wLb_gk</id>
<title><![CDATA[PAPER ORCHID - MARATHI - Simple, beautiful Orchid!]]></title>
<duration>3:33</duration>
<date>2014-03-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make this simple and beautiful orchid by cutting and taping color paper. The whole process is very simple and the end product is extremely aesthetic and appealing to the eye! http://arvindguptatoys...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>f0pA0SQrPP0</id>
<title><![CDATA[MAGNETIC SPIN AND ROLL - MARATHI - Fun with magnets!]]></title>
<duration>2:06</duration>
<date>2014-03-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[Take a bottle lid with a rounded base. Stick some ring magnets with rubber adhesive inside the lid. Stick a card sheet doll on a refill and embed the other end in the ring magnets. Now stick...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>d1z0GHREOo8</id>
<title><![CDATA[TRACING PATH OF LIGHT - MARATHI - Most Spectacular Experiment!]]></title>
<duration>1:30</duration>
<date>2014-03-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[We know that light travels in straight lines. But do you visually show this? You will need a toy laser and some chalk dust. In a dark room shine the laser on the far away wall and you will...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>wJufQcCemw0</id>
<title><![CDATA[SHIFTING LIGHT USING SCALE - MARATHI - Scale as Prism!]]></title>
<duration>1:20</duration>
<date>2014-03-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[Shine a laser on the front wall and you will see a spot on the wall. Now bring a plastic scale its tapered part between the beam of light. The spot on the wall will shift. This is because of...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>iyE7G4PKYog</id>
<title><![CDATA[BUDDY TOP - MARATHI - A natural Top!]]></title>
<duration>1:51</duration>
<date>2014-03-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[Take a bud of the Silk Cotton Tree -- which produces the famous kapok used for filling soft pillows. Hold the bud stem and twirl it like a top. It will keep spinning for a long time. If the...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Mn5svnph1Tg</id>
<title><![CDATA[A C  MOTOR - MARATHI - AC motor from Salvaged Choke!]]></title>
<duration>3:40</duration>
<date>2014-03-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[Salvage the core material from a fused tube light choke. Arrange them in a 'C' shape so that there is a gap between them. Place a coil with 1200 turns (30-guage) of Insulated Copper Wire. Attach...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>GmPJximFtL4</id>
<title><![CDATA[HELICOPTER FLOWER  - MARATHI - Natural flower spins like a helicopter!]]></title>
<duration>1:05</duration>
<date>2014-03-06</date>
<description><![CDATA[This natural flower when thrown from top comes spinning down like a helicopter!]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>pUDer8FS43Q</id>
<title><![CDATA[VIBRATING BRUSH - MARATHI - Fun with a Mobile Motor!]]></title>
<duration>1:37</duration>
<date>2014-03-06</date>
<description><![CDATA[At the heart of this toy is the vibrator motor from an old mobile phone. The motor is mounted on a plastic brush used for scrubbing. The motor has a one-blade fan. As the motor vibrates the...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>6icjCrcGCWs</id>
<title><![CDATA[UP DOWN DOLL  - MARATHI - Marvelous mechanism, Fun toy!]]></title>
<duration>2:06</duration>
<date>2014-03-06</date>
<description><![CDATA[For making this toy you will need a plastic bottle, straws, card sheet and other simple stuff. On pressing the bottle the doll attached to the straw will go up. On releasing pressure the doll...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>7fnmYWf-jas</id>
<title><![CDATA[CUP CHANDELIER - MARATHI - Fun with rubber band!]]></title>
<duration>4:33</duration>
<date>2014-02-21</date>
<description><![CDATA[With the help of a twisted rubber band you can rotate a cup. The beads tied around the rim of the cup with thread will spin and the cup will look like a chandelier. http://arvindguptatoys.com/toys...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>mAdsUSi5aig</id>
<title><![CDATA[LIFTING JACK - MARATHI - Amazing Hydraulic Jack!]]></title>
<duration>4:22</duration>
<date>2014-02-21</date>
<description><![CDATA[Get a feel for hydraulic jack. Using two new plastic syringes (minus the needles) and a few ice-cream sticks you can make a Jack to lift a load. The syringes transit force through the water...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>F3IJtpgRYvo</id>
<title><![CDATA[COIN SPINNER - MARATHI - Simple, traditional, spinning toy!]]></title>
<duration>0:57</duration>
<date>2014-01-17</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is a traditional spinning toy. Many of the coins in India were made of Aluminum. Take an Aluminum coin and lift it up with the help of two long needles. You can easily do it by poking...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Py255mpclFU</id>
<title><![CDATA[AERO BIRD - MARATHI - Amazing flapping Bird of Paradise!]]></title>
<duration>2:07</duration>
<date>2014-01-09</date>
<description><![CDATA[This wonderful bird can be cut and folded from a piece of paper. The bird looks very elegant. You hold its neck with one hand and then as you pull the triangular tab the bird will flap its...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Y4mt46KKyho</id>
<title><![CDATA[STATIC STRAWS - MARATHI - Fun with Static Electricity!]]></title>
<duration>2:17</duration>
<date>2014-01-09</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make a large hole on the end of a dozen straws. Tie a 20-cm long thread on each straw. Then tie all the threads together. Now rub the straws with a woolen cloth. This will charge the straws...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Gf42_Hft7CE</id>
<title><![CDATA[BOTTLE CENTRIFUGE - MARATHI - Simple centrifuge!]]></title>
<duration>1:49</duration>
<date>2014-01-09</date>
<description><![CDATA[Fix a straw in the middle of a plastic bottle. Seal the ends. Place some color water in the bottle. Now place a cycle spoke in the straw and spin the bottle. The force of spin will throw the...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>IotGjvhhX-Q</id>
<title><![CDATA[WAGGING TAIL - MARATHI - Doll with a wagging tail!]]></title>
<duration>2:54</duration>
<date>2014-01-09</date>
<description><![CDATA[This toy is made by the indigenous people in India and was introduced to us by Sourabh Phadke. The dog's tail is made by joining two thin broomsticks on top and then weaving a paper strip....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>iuvB-RUdevY</id>
<title><![CDATA[TETRA PURSE WITH LOCK - MARATHI - Water proof, lockable purse!]]></title>
<duration>2:50</duration>
<date>2014-01-09</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make this amazing purse from a 1-litre tetrapack. You need to flatten and cut the tetrapack into an oval shape. Then mark, score and fold lines at 30-degrees. In the end you gather the folds...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>M6cYgLwQ1ZI</id>
<title><![CDATA[VERTICAL LEVITATION - MARATHI - Standing pencil, Spinning pencil!]]></title>
<duration>2:55</duration>
<date>2014-01-09</date>
<description><![CDATA[Push a writing tip in the base of a writing pen so that there are tips on both ends. Press fit a bottle fan in the middle. The pen is levitated from below because of magnets with same poles...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>HFD5pSZJBuQ</id>
<title><![CDATA[BUDDHIST SINGING BOWL - MARATHI - Sounds grows into a crescendo!]]></title>
<duration>1:58</duration>
<date>2014-01-09</date>
<description><![CDATA[The bronze Buddhist bowl makes spectacular and melodious sounds. Place the bowl on a book such that the bowl does not rotate. Then tap the rim of the bowl with a wooden stick to start the resonance ...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>QjrYKVVbdNI</id>
<title><![CDATA[TEN HOUR CLOCK FACE - MARATHI - Fold a circle into 10 equal sectors.]]></title>
<duration>3:31</duration>
<date>2013-12-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[How do you fold a circle into ten equal sectors to make a ten hour clock face. This is challenging but can be easily. This is a wonderful exercise in practical geometry -- where you learn the...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>H-kotXCgFeI</id>
<title><![CDATA[IRREGULAR PAPER TO SQUARE - MARATHI - How to fold a square?]]></title>
<duration>2:02</duration>
<date>2013-12-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[Given an uneven piece of paper how do you fold a regular square? This simple and fun exercise will test a lot of your theoretical geometry and will give you hours of fun.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>JKrUnzztd5g</id>
<title><![CDATA[CONGRUENT TRIANGLES (SSS) RULE - MARATHI - Fun with triangles.]]></title>
<duration>2:57</duration>
<date>2013-12-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[If the three sides of one triangle are equal to the three sides of another triangle than both these triangles are congruent according to the side-side-side rule. This can be easily proved with...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>32OporcmI7g</id>
<title><![CDATA[PAPER GANESH - MARATHI - Fold the Indian God Ganesha with a square.]]></title>
<duration>3:31</duration>
<date>2013-12-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[With a piece of paper square you can fold and make a 3-dimension sculptor of Lord Ganesha -- the Indian deity who blessings are invoked before undertaking any new task.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>iqG_wUJqZeA</id>
<title><![CDATA[REGULAR HEXAGON - MARATHI - Fold a hexagon from a square paper.]]></title>
<duration>2:30</duration>
<date>2013-12-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[With a piece of square paper you can fold a fairly accurate regular hexagon. This is a creative way to learn the properties of a hexagon and how to fold it from a square piece of paper.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>e_CENmpXBzs</id>
<title><![CDATA[SQUARE TO PRISM - MARATHI - Fold a paper square into a Prism.]]></title>
<duration>3:02</duration>
<date>2013-12-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[It is interesting to fold a 3-dimensional prism from a piece of square. The Prism looks like a tent shape. The model uses no glue or scissors.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>fJs1-36U6WM</id>
<title><![CDATA[REPELLING WATER - MARATHI - Water being diamagnetic can be repelled with magnets.]]></title>
<duration>1:46</duration>
<date>2013-12-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[Float a test tube filled with water on a piece of foam in a big bowl of water. Bring strong neodymium magnets near the vertical tube. Do not touch the tube. Water is diamagnetic in nature and...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>kvbmD5-R4RI</id>
<title><![CDATA[CD FAN - MARATHI - Make a spinner from an old CD.]]></title>
<duration>2:31</duration>
<date>2013-12-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make a spinning fan from an old CD. First mark and cut 16 equal sectors in the CD. The break alternate petals so that just 8 petals remain. Heat the base of each petal under a candle flame...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>kysGVV3rtXw</id>
<title><![CDATA[MUSHROOM CLOUD - MARATHI - A falling milk drop in water makes a mushroom cloud!]]></title>
<duration>1:44</duration>
<date>2013-12-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[When you place a high density drop in a low-density liquid the effect is called as Rayleigh-Taylor Effect and results in formation of a mushroom cloud or vortexes. Place a drop of milk in a...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>hF95N0Kx8Lk</id>
<title><![CDATA[MISSING VOLUME - MARATHI - Where did it go?]]></title>
<duration>1:50</duration>
<date>2013-12-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[Measure 25-ml of water in a measuring cylinder and pour it in a transparent plastic glass. Then measure 25-ml of Isopropyl Alcohol (antiseptic spirit) in a measuring cylinder and pour in the...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Zc9CXrdIyRI</id>
<title><![CDATA[CLOUDS IN WATER - MARATHI - A milk drop in different densities of liquid.]]></title>
<duration>2:15</duration>
<date>2013-12-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[As you put drops of color in glasses with different densities of liquids you see different patterns. In water the color drops settles to the bottom, in glycerine it simply floats on the surface,...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>t86AN4hk4DA</id>
<title><![CDATA[BALANCING DOOR GUARD - MARATHI - Beautiful Balancing Toy!]]></title>
<duration>2:30</duration>
<date>2013-12-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is essentially a balancing toy with a low center of gravity. You can place this on your door knob to let your friends know whether they are WELCOME TO COME IN or else, you are busy and...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>G13YJBj6M-Q</id>
<title><![CDATA[COLOUR MAGIC - MARATHI - Amazing Christmas Card!]]></title>
<duration>2:17</duration>
<date>2013-12-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[This Magic Card will delight any child. Make a drawing with color pencils on a thick white card. DO NOT draw the OUTLINE. Place a transparency of the same size on the card. Tape both the card...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>UbfXakAYE-Y</id>
<title><![CDATA[PUPPET FROM TRASH - MARATHI - A walking, hand-clapping puppet!]]></title>
<duration>2:13</duration>
<date>2013-12-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[This moving, walking, clapping marionette puppet can be made of scrap materials. There are two sticks at right angles embedded in an old ball. There are five strings attached to the sticks...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>v_N6kYXx9w8</id>
<title><![CDATA[BRAIN MUSCLE COORDINATION - MARATHI - Involuntary reflex!]]></title>
<duration>0:55</duration>
<date>2013-12-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[This experiment shows the link between our muscles and our brain. You place 2-Kgs of books on the left hand of a friend. Let her hold them for just 5-seconds. Then as you unburden her with...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>epsCnclAWkw</id>
<title><![CDATA[INDIAN SNAKE TRICK - MARATHI - Science behind a popular cracker]]></title>
<duration>1:16</duration>
<date>2013-12-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[In India, during Diwali -- the festival of LIGHTS all kinds of firecrackers are sold. It's during this time that the BLACK SNAKE tablets are readily available. As you light each tablet with...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>PCnj5svFYV8</id>
<title><![CDATA[SECRET SCRIPT - MARATHI - Read between the lines!]]></title>
<duration>2:22</duration>
<date>2013-12-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[A very interesting toy made with simple materials. Take a transparent CD and with a marker write the alphabets A, B, C, D etc. on the CD in a very random manner. Stick a marble in the center...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>OEnStbh5dnk</id>
<title><![CDATA[SWIRL COATING - MARATHI - Wonderful Marble Painting!]]></title>
<duration>2:29</duration>
<date>2013-12-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[Place a few drops of white oil paint (used for painting doors) in a tub of water. The paint will float on the surface. Mix well. Then add a few drops of red and yellow paint too. On mixing...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Caas0u9lCxA</id>
<title><![CDATA[STICK TRANSMISSION - MARATHI - Fantastic Force Transmission!]]></title>
<duration>1:49</duration>
<date>2013-12-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is a fantastic low-cost science activity. It does not need any fancy equipment. All you need is a few matchsticks. Place a matchstick on the table. Keep the second across the first. Keep...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>vz6qJvLuifE</id>
<title><![CDATA[COLOUR WINDOW - MARATHI - Amazing Christmas Greeting Card!]]></title>
<duration>2:38</duration>
<date>2013-12-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is a magical experiment. All you need is a transparency, some paper, color pencils and a marker. Make a colorful drawing -- a landscape on a card sheet with color pencils. DO NOT MAKE...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>wkldtsP-KKg</id>
<title><![CDATA[WATER PROOF NET - MARATHI - Surface Tension in Action!]]></title>
<duration>2:10</duration>
<date>2013-12-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[This classic experiment was first conducted by experimental doyen C. V. Boys in 1883. Fill a glass to the brim with water and covered it with a mosquito net. Tighten the net and keep it in...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>FVQ5WuuCJuw</id>
<title><![CDATA[MERRY GO ROUND - MARATHI - Earth-Sun Model!]]></title>
<duration>2:43</duration>
<date>2013-12-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[A card fan with blades is mounted on one end of a spoke. On the other end is a bead stopper. The second spoke has two magnets. The spoke of the fan sticks to the ring magnets. When placed under...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>3ctJP67KmtI</id>
<title><![CDATA[FOUNTAIN ON FINGERTIP - MARATHI - Simple Fun Fountain!]]></title>
<duration>1:57</duration>
<date>2013-12-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is a fun experiment. Take a small transparent plastic bottle. Make a small hole in its base. Make a big hole in its lid and press fit a dropper tube in it. The orifice of the dropper tube...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>IMK02VLVvOM</id>
<title><![CDATA[STATIC BALLOON - MARATHI - A truly hair raising experience!]]></title>
<duration>1:43</duration>
<date>2013-12-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[Inflate a balloon and tie a knot. Bring it close to your hair and head and nothing would happen. Now rub the balloon on your hair. This will knock down a few electrons and the balloon will...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>gko1dU6bmrw</id>
<title><![CDATA[STATIC CHARGE BENDS WATER - MARATHI - Power of static electricity!]]></title>
<duration>1:41</duration>
<date>2013-12-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[Fill a bottle with water and place it on a perch. Then make a small hole with a needle near the bottle base. A thin stream of water will gush out. Bring an ordinary comb near the water stream...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>3_wgHG1X9Vw</id>
<title><![CDATA[CLOCK DIAL FROM A CIRCLE - MARATHI - Fold a Circle in 12 equal sectors.]]></title>
<duration>3:01</duration>
<date>2013-12-13</date>
<description><![CDATA[This wonderful activity shows how to fold a circle into 12-equal sectors to make a clock dial face. This is a very creative and challenging paper folding activity.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>p95HTkJvx9c</id>
<title><![CDATA[SIMILAR TRIANGLES - MARATHI - Fold and have fun with Similar Triangles.]]></title>
<duration>2:32</duration>
<date>2013-12-13</date>
<description><![CDATA[Explore some wonderful properties of Similar Triangles through paper folding.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>jzrAnVxeid8</id>
<title><![CDATA[AREA OF TRIANGLE - MARATHI - Estimate the Area of a Triangle.]]></title>
<duration>3:38</duration>
<date>2013-12-13</date>
<description><![CDATA[With the help of tracing paper you can explore many properties of a triangle. For instance, you can visually see that the sum of the angles of a triangle is equal to 180-degrees.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>GmRbgM3kAes</id>
<title><![CDATA[FUN WITH TRIANGLE - MARATHI - Great fun with paper triangles.]]></title>
<duration>2:07</duration>
<date>2013-12-13</date>
<description><![CDATA[With the help of tracing paper you can explore many properties of a triangle. For instance, you can visually see that the sum of the angles of a triangle is equal to 180-degrees. Also that...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>1Ewqw_nm8Vg</id>
<title><![CDATA[CIRCLE TO CONE - MARATHI - Fold a Cone from a Circle.]]></title>
<duration>5:01</duration>
<date>2013-12-13</date>
<description><![CDATA[You can fold a CONE from a circle. To make the circle however, you will need a rectangular sheet of paper 29.6-cm long and 8.8-cm broad. Once you have made the circle from the rectangle then...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>O2UWFnydnek</id>
<title><![CDATA[AREA OF CIRCLE - MARATHI - Estimate the Area of a Circle.]]></title>
<duration>3:39</duration>
<date>2013-12-13</date>
<description><![CDATA[From a rectangular sheet of paper (with definite dimensions) you can fold a circle and the approximate its area. It is surprise many that a circle can be folded from a rectangle and will open...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>E_820q8jDPU</id>
<title><![CDATA[PAPER BOX  - MARATHI - Fold a Box from a piece of paper.]]></title>
<duration>3:15</duration>
<date>2013-12-13</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make a rectangular box by folding an old A-4 size Xerox sheet. A box of this size will hold approximately 1-liter of water. This Fun, Low-cost Maths will help children understand the nitty-gritty's...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>cy0xbLFE7uE</id>
<title><![CDATA[FOLD A CIRCLE - MARATHI - Fold a Circle from a rectangular strip.]]></title>
<duration>3:59</duration>
<date>2013-12-13</date>
<description><![CDATA[From a rectangular sheet of paper (with definite dimensions) you can fold a circle and the approximate its circumference. It is surprise many that a circle can be folded from a rectangle and...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>dnO6qyQ2fU8</id>
<title><![CDATA[SQUARE TO HEPTAGON - MARATHI - Fold a regular Heptagon from a paper square.]]></title>
<duration>6:11</duration>
<date>2013-12-13</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make a regular HEPTAGON by folding a square. Paper folding by its very nature is binary. Keep doubling paper to have 2, 4, 8, 16, 30 folds. These are all binary numbers. But how do you fold...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>EkyGCk4DeVk</id>
<title><![CDATA[PAPER CUBE - MARATHI - Fold a Cube from a paper square.]]></title>
<duration>3:18</duration>
<date>2013-12-13</date>
<description><![CDATA[Fold a self-locked CUBE from an A-4 size Xerox Paper. This cube uses no scissors or glue. Once you make a CUBE there is a whole world based on the cube. You can make a Dice or a Soma's Cube.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>JXqYyc9bCMI</id>
<title><![CDATA[SQUARE TO PENTAGON - MARATHI - Fold a regular Pentagon from a paper square.]]></title>
<duration>4:27</duration>
<date>2013-12-13</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make a regular PENTAGON by folding a square. Paper folding by its very nature is binary. Keep doubling paper to have 2, 4, 8, 16, 30 folds. These are all binary numbers. But how do you fold...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Ijue2nK8bJY</id>
<title><![CDATA[SQUARE TO CUBE - MARATHI - Fold a Cube from a paper square.]]></title>
<duration>2:13</duration>
<date>2013-12-13</date>
<description><![CDATA[Without using any glue or scissors fold a paper square to make a self-locked cube. This wonderful Origami helps you fold a cube from a square paper. Once you have a CUBE you make Dices out...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>POs_ybXlxsM</id>
<title><![CDATA[PAPER CUP FISH - MARATHI - Amazing Fish from throwaway paper cup]]></title>
<duration>2:21</duration>
<date>2013-12-13</date>
<description><![CDATA[From the base of a paper cup you can make an exquisite fish. Make sea waves using a card. Decorate it with colorful seaweeds and place the fishes to make a jaw dropping 3-D paper mural. http://www.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>nO9b4bXpiTA</id>
<title><![CDATA[MAGNETIC FAN - MARATHI - This spinning action is akin to Moon-Earth Model.]]></title>
<duration>2:49</duration>
<date>2013-12-13</date>
<description><![CDATA[Attach a small wooden screw to a pen body and hang it from a magnet. Fix a card propeller to the pen end. Attach a cycle nut to the pen to stabilize it. On placing the toy under a ceiling fan...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>TgyALddIZrE</id>
<title><![CDATA[PAPER PUPPET - MARATHI - Dynamic, Talking Fun Puppet]]></title>
<duration>2:26</duration>
<date>2013-12-13</date>
<description><![CDATA[Take a printout of the template on a card sheet. Cut and paste them together to make a talking puppet. Stick orange paper in the mouth. Hold the puppet and move your fingers to open and close...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>6FgwEJT3mak</id>
<title><![CDATA[HOLE IN SPINNING WATER - MARATHI - See Centrifugal Force in Action.]]></title>
<duration>2:30</duration>
<date>2013-12-13</date>
<description><![CDATA[Hang a fused electric light bulb with the filament removed with a short thread. Fill the bulb one-third with water. Spin the bulb so that the thread twists completely. On releasing, the bulb...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>w86qDMf9nC4</id>
<title><![CDATA[EASY BALANCE - MARATHI - Wonderful Balancing Toy.]]></title>
<duration>2:56</duration>
<date>2013-12-13</date>
<description><![CDATA[Cut a card butterfly or figurine. Attach two press-buttons on the wing tips and another near the center. Then perch the middle press button on a toothpick. The butterfly or figurine will balance...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>yapGl69r82I</id>
<title><![CDATA[PULL WATER - MARATHI - Create Vacuum, Pull Water.]]></title>
<duration>2:17</duration>
<date>2013-12-13</date>
<description><![CDATA[Water flowing from the lower end of a bottle creates a partial vacuum and sucks water from an adjacent jar. This is a very creative experiment on water and air. http://www.arvindguptatoys.com/toys/...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>E94DH7hqwEw</id>
<title><![CDATA[COLOUR WINDOW - MARATHI - Amazing Magical Card for New Year]]></title>
<duration>2:38</duration>
<date>2013-12-04</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make a drawing with color pencils (without the border) and stick in under the window of an envelope. Then draw the outline or border of the picture on the window transparency with a marker...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>f5ZBn3yHwOs</id>
<title><![CDATA[ROTATE PROPELLER SPIN DOLL - MARATHI - A wonderful Spinning Doll made from odds and bits]]></title>
<duration>1:52</duration>
<date>2013-12-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[In this toy a plastic bottle propeller spins under the ceiling fan. The propeller axle has a doll mounted on it. On placing the toy under a ceiling fan the bottle propeller spins and this in...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>y9gJWbDZjx4</id>
<title><![CDATA[STICK TRANSMISSION - MARATHI - Transmit a force through a long matchstick chain]]></title>
<duration>1:49</duration>
<date>2013-12-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[By placing matchsticks in a particular fashion you can make a large chain. The sticks are placed one across the other. As you press the last matchstick the first one will be lifted! http://www.arvi...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>p6YZ0ho3cPk</id>
<title><![CDATA[REPELLING WATER - MARATHI - Water is diamagnetic and can be repelled by magnets]]></title>
<duration>1:46</duration>
<date>2013-12-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[Float a test tube filled with water on a piece of foam in a big bowl of water. Bring strong neodymium magnets near the vertical tube. Do not touch the tube. Water is diamagnetic in nature and...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>vugeUKAkz9M</id>
<title><![CDATA[FLYING FLAME - MARATHI - Make a mini hot air balloon]]></title>
<duration>1:47</duration>
<date>2013-12-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is an easy to make hot air balloon. Empty a tea bag and stand the absorbent paper bag like a cylinder in a ceramic plate. Now light the top of the cylinder. The burning tea bag will take...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>mbp1pm3Tprc</id>
<title><![CDATA[STRIP TO TETRAHEDRON - MARATHI - Fold a tetrahedron from a paper strip]]></title>
<duration>1:44</duration>
<date>2013-12-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[Fold a strip of paper 28-cm long and 4-cm wide into a circular hoop. Fold along midline and divide it into quarters. Now unfold the strip and open it like a boat. On bringing the edges together...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DAcXzbe0KN0</id>
<title><![CDATA[BOTTLE SPIDER - MARATHI - Amazing Spider from a throwaway bottle.]]></title>
<duration>2:36</duration>
<date>2013-11-25</date>
<description><![CDATA[This creepy crawly creature made from junk stuff actually moves. On loosening, the thread gets wrapped on a battery and this twists a rubber band. On pulling, the rubber band unwinds and the...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>tEtRPpSt6Xc</id>
<title><![CDATA[FLOPPY ART -  MARATHI - Fun Art from old Floppy Discs.]]></title>
<duration>1:40</duration>
<date>2013-11-24</date>
<description><![CDATA[Old floppy discs are simply thrown away because 1.44 MB of data means little. Salvage Aluminum parts from an old Floppy Disc and make wonderful artifacts -- like a chair, a dinosaur or a goat....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>zeymVHY4hNo</id>
<title><![CDATA[3-D SHAPES - MARATHI - 37MB]]></title>
<duration>3:57</duration>
<date>2013-10-17</date>
<description><![CDATA[From old toothpaste cartons and boxes with square cross-section you can make amazing 3 dimensional cubical box, hexagonal box and an octagonal box.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>xMqBOufGJZU</id>
<title><![CDATA[CORRUGATED FAN - MARATHI - 25MB]]></title>
<duration>3:19</duration>
<date>2013-10-17</date>
<description><![CDATA[Fan-fold a long card strip to make a long corrugated strip. Stick it to a paper cup. Cut small lugs and twist them into blades. On placing under a fan the toy will spin beautifully. http://arvindgu...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>U07TimpeCQU</id>
<title><![CDATA[BALLOON BOTTLE FOUNTAIN - MARATHI - 16MB]]></title>
<duration>2:09</duration>
<date>2013-10-17</date>
<description><![CDATA[Press fit a stiff straw near the base of a stiff plastic bottle. Now place a balloon in the bottle and stretch its mouth on the bottle. On sucking from the stiff straw the balloon will inflate...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>eiYWa34m5Zk</id>
<title><![CDATA[THREE BOTTLE FOUNTAIN - MARATHI - 38MB]]></title>
<duration>4:02</duration>
<date>2013-10-17</date>
<description><![CDATA[Plastic bottles are aplenty today. With three plastic bottles, a stiff straw and two flexi-tubes you can easily make the famous Heron's Fountain. Water from the top (cut) bottle enters the...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>1sUtVTKVhFE</id>
<title><![CDATA[FINGER MULTIPLICATION - MARATHI - 31MB]]></title>
<duration>5:07</duration>
<date>2013-10-17</date>
<description><![CDATA[Using fingers of both hands you can easily do two digit multiplications of numbers between 6 and 10. This is a wonderful way of activity based multiplication. This technique is very apt for...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>x6r2S1YvZfI</id>
<title><![CDATA[SUPER SPINNING BOTTLE - MARATHI - 14MB]]></title>
<duration>1:37</duration>
<date>2013-10-17</date>
<description><![CDATA[Cut 5 petals in a half a liter bottle. Then fold and twist them to make fan blades. Weave a cycle spoke in the holes of the lid and base. On placing the bottle under a ceiling fan this Super...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>18zV-5DNctA</id>
<title><![CDATA[HOME MADE STAR VIEWER - MARATHI - 17MB]]></title>
<duration>2:06</duration>
<date>2013-10-17</date>
<description><![CDATA[This star viewer was designed as a readymade kit by LG of Korea. Some constellations are marked on a card. The stars are marked with LEDs. On switching the LEDs the major stars in the constellation.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>w9hdg7DBx9g</id>
<title><![CDATA[STRING MOSQUITO - MARATHI - 6MB]]></title>
<duration>1:12</duration>
<date>2013-10-17</date>
<description><![CDATA[With a 1.8-m long string loop you can make an X shaped mosquito. The 'hums and buzzes' near your year. You crush it with a clap of your palms. When you pull your hands apart the mosquito ...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>oA6VV23R8R4</id>
<title><![CDATA[NEWTON'S BOAT -  MARATHI  - 10MB]]></title>
<duration>1:32</duration>
<date>2013-10-16</date>
<description><![CDATA[This floating boat has a toy motor with a propeller mounted on it. When the boat is placed in water the whirring motor throws air backwards and the boat propels forwards. It illustrates Newton's...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>N_6JdZnRaa0</id>
<title><![CDATA[PRETTY BUTTERFLY  -  MARATHI - 11MB]]></title>
<duration>1:34</duration>
<date>2013-10-16</date>
<description><![CDATA[At the heart of this beautiful butterfly is a crank. As you rotate the crank the wings of the butterfly lift and fall and the butterfly appears to be flapping its wings. http://www.arvindguptatoys...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>-j2fuBIK_Oc</id>
<title><![CDATA[SOLAR BOAT - MARATHI]]></title>
<duration>2:21</duration>
<date>2013-10-15</date>
<description><![CDATA[This Solar Boat has been designed by LG / Korea. A solar panel creates electricity which runs an electric motor which in turn rotates the paddles of a boat. When placed in water under the sun...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>-_NwfJqmPKY</id>
<title><![CDATA[AEROMODELLING - MARATHI - 16MB]]></title>
<duration>2:21</duration>
<date>2013-10-15</date>
<description><![CDATA[This video shows the working of a remote controlled airplane model powered by an electric motor. Once the airplane takes off it can be controlled from the ground. The airplane can climb, turn,...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>4ZKG9S4zp4Q</id>
<title><![CDATA[STAY PUT COINS - MARATHI - 8MB]]></title>
<duration>1:11</duration>
<date>2013-10-15</date>
<description><![CDATA[This fun experiment demonstrates inertia using coins and paper strips. A paper strip is placed on a bottle lid. Stand a coin vertically on this strip. Hit the free end of the strip hard with...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>9u4w4WR00v0</id>
<title><![CDATA[BROOM STICK MODELS - MARATHI - 15MB]]></title>
<duration>1:59</duration>
<date>2013-10-15</date>
<description><![CDATA[Broomsticks can be found in the poorest Indian home. Take six 15-cm long broomsticks and tie their ends with rubber bands or thread to make a Tetrahedron. Similarly make many 3-D modules and...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>RTEan0_pNL4</id>
<title><![CDATA[SURFACE SIZE - MARATHI - 11MB]]></title>
<duration>1:29</duration>
<date>2013-10-15</date>
<description><![CDATA[This experiment is to do with surface size. Take a normal straw, cut the other at a slant and cut four petals in the third. Dip each straw in soap solution and blow. The first straw will produce...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DcT1wfblaYY</id>
<title><![CDATA[TWO WAY TURBINE - MARATHI - 18MB]]></title>
<duration>2:14</duration>
<date>2013-10-15</date>
<description><![CDATA[This 2-way turbine consists of two separate turbines made from plastic bottles. The turbines are made by cutting a dozen petals in the bottles and then twisting them to make fan blades. On...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>AFhXhNVvwyA</id>
<title><![CDATA[INDIAN CLAY DRUM - MARATHI - 12MB]]></title>
<duration>1:25</duration>
<date>2013-10-15</date>
<description><![CDATA[This kind of clay drum was found during the excavation of Mohenjo-Daro and Harappa more than 5000 years ago. On pulling the cart, the clay wheels turn and two sticks repeatedly strike a drum...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>MdfeI_pBQwE</id>
<title><![CDATA[JUMPING COIL - MARATHI - 13MB]]></title>
<duration>1:51</duration>
<date>2013-10-15</date>
<description><![CDATA[Place an insulated copper wire coil loosely on top of a pencil battery. The battery stands on a permanent magnet. When current flows through the coil it becomes an electromagnet. The coil is...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>ntpEzA-ptOo</id>
<title><![CDATA[SLITHERING SNAKE - MARATHI - 11MB]]></title>
<duration>1:38</duration>
<date>2013-10-15</date>
<description><![CDATA[Generations of Indian children have played with this traditional Indian toy. As you pull a thin thread the snake lunges forward. On loosing the thread it goes back. This snake beautifully imitates...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>bYayh1-w4hQ</id>
<title><![CDATA[LINK MECHANISM - MARATHI - 7MB]]></title>
<duration>0:57</duration>
<date>2013-10-15</date>
<description><![CDATA[This very beautiful link mechanism can be made from thick card sheet, pen refills, flexi-board, wire and an old plastic bottle. As you turn the crank both the arms of the link mechanism start...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>1AEDaSEc3yg</id>
<title><![CDATA[WIRE LIZARD - MARATHI - 7MB]]></title>
<duration>1:06</duration>
<date>2013-10-15</date>
<description><![CDATA[This toy is based on a double crank. On rotating the crank all the four legs of the lizard move in unison imitating the walk of a real lizard as if it was climbing a wall. http://www.arvindgupta...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>JHT734MC25s</id>
<title><![CDATA[ROCKING TOY - MARATHI - 8MB]]></title>
<duration>1:19</duration>
<date>2013-10-15</date>
<description><![CDATA[The rocking toy is great fun. Two cycle spokes are inserted at an angle in a lid with two crazy balls hang below lowering its center of gravity. The toy happily balances on a pivot. When rocked...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>ElHAV_PjOh8</id>
<title><![CDATA[MODEL OF EYE - MARATHI - 16MB]]></title>
<duration>2:10</duration>
<date>2013-10-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is a wonderful model of the eye. It is made with a large size plastic ball. A tube on one end has a convex lens. On the other end is a sliding screen -- like the retina. By adjusting the...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>0dJEKB5MrGI</id>
<title><![CDATA[HOT ICE - MARATHI - 13MB]]></title>
<duration>1:50</duration>
<date>2013-10-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[Boil 1-litre of vinegar with 4 teaspoons of baking soda until 90% of the water evaporates. This will be a saturated solution. Place it in a glass for 6 hours to cool. Then sprinkle a few grains...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>XLGVv9ecV0I</id>
<title><![CDATA[STRAW PETALS FAN - MARATHI - 12MB]]></title>
<duration>1:37</duration>
<date>2013-10-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[MAKE A WONDERFUL SPINNING FAN FROM TWO STRAWS!]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>utEc5p3IfDU</id>
<title><![CDATA[LEVITATING MAN -  MARATHI - 5MB]]></title>
<duration>1:00</duration>
<date>2013-10-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[A FUN TOYS MADE FROM A STEEL BALL & A STRONG MAGNET !]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>9SBcZ4nQ-4c</id>
<title><![CDATA[CELESTIAL CRATERS - MARATHI - 15MB]]></title>
<duration>1:53</duration>
<date>2013-10-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[THIS SIMPLE EXPERIMENT DEMONSTRATES THE FORMATION OF CRATERS !]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Cnc3Dq7f60U</id>
<title><![CDATA[BALANCING WIREMAN - MARATHI - 6MB]]></title>
<duration>1:00</duration>
<date>2013-10-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[The wireman has long arms with heavy weights which lower its center of gravity. Place it on top of a stick and give it a little twirl. The toy will rock and spin and dance to your amusement....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>ZM2KJ0T4Nbk</id>
<title><![CDATA[TWISTED HOOP - MARATHI - 14MB]]></title>
<duration>1:49</duration>
<date>2013-10-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[You will need two aluminum cups and some strips of paper to make this spinning hoop. Lugs are cut from the cups and 4 strips are joined to make a hoop. The twisted lugs and paper strips act...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>ZGXRp6UJzoo</id>
<title><![CDATA[BALLOON BENCH - MARATHI - 9MB]]></title>
<duration>1:21</duration>
<date>2013-10-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[Inflate 4 good quality balloons and tie them together with their mouths. Place some newspapers on the balloons and then a thick wooden plank. This balloon bench will be able to take the load...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>3-E0CylcbLI</id>
<title><![CDATA[MAGNETIC ZOOM - MARATHI - 7MB]]></title>
<duration>1:28</duration>
<date>2013-10-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[The Magnetic Zoom is a terrific science project. Strong neodymium magnets attract a steel ball from the left and another one is ejected from the right at high speed. This process can be further...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>HQAyxa0neBQ</id>
<title><![CDATA[WALKING THROUGH A POSTCARD - MARATHI - 16MB]]></title>
<duration>2:00</duration>
<date>2013-10-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[Can you walk through a postcard? It seems impossible, but it's actually true. Fold and cut the postcard so that it becomes a big garland. Gently open the garland and it will be big enough for...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>pgl2EAGOejc</id>
<title><![CDATA[CANDLE SEESAW - MARATHI - 8MB]]></title>
<duration>1:19</duration>
<date>2013-10-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[A candle with lighted wicks on both ends is delicately pivoted on a needle axle. As wax drips from one end it becomes lighter and the candle tips the other way. The candle does a see-saw dance...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>9u2go8bmra8</id>
<title><![CDATA[DOLL ON ROPE - MARATHI - 13MB]]></title>
<duration>1:42</duration>
<date>2013-10-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[Remove the metal discs of two old floppies and stick them back-to-back to make a smooth pulley. Place this pulley in a 'U' wire frame weighted with heavy nuts to lower its center of gravity....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>P057cF9ObDE</id>
<title><![CDATA[BALANCING BOY - MARATHI - 8MB]]></title>
<duration>1:15</duration>
<date>2013-10-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[The Balancing Boy is made from all kinds of odd things -- plastic boxes, lids, toothpaste tubes etc. A few ring magnets are stuck to make the body heavy and easy to balance. On giving it a...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>NkqI6KhvcZ4</id>
<title><![CDATA[CRANKY CRANK - MARATHI  - 10MB]]></title>
<duration>1:27</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[In this interesting toy as you rotate a crank a beautiful butterfly flaps its wings. The crank is mounted in a plastic bottle. The rotating crank moves a straw con rod which lifts and lowers...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>aSDNcBs3aZw</id>
<title><![CDATA[SPOON PROPELLOR -  MARATHI - 9MB]]></title>
<duration>1:16</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[The fan blades of this propeller are made of two plastic spoons embedded in an eraser. The eraser has a wooden stick as axle which can spin in a straw. When placed under a ceiling fan air strikes...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>tuCI27RWkoM</id>
<title><![CDATA[CYCLIST ON ROPE - MARATHI - 5MB]]></title>
<duration>0:47</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[The cyclist on the rope is a fascinating toy. The cycle frame is mounted on two pulleys. A heavy weight hangs down the frame. This lowers its center of gravity and provides it stability. Place...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>w-bAKiYBk90</id>
<title><![CDATA[STICK MAN -  MARATHI -  6MB]]></title>
<duration>0:54</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[This Stick Man is essentially a balancing toy which is made by gluing or stapling a few ice cream sticks. The stickman's legs are weighted down with magnets. This lowers its center of gravity...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>nSoJVRmegdA</id>
<title><![CDATA[BOBBING BUTTERFLY - MARATHI  - 12MB]]></title>
<duration>1:28</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[The Bobbing Butterfly is an extremely creative toy. Two similar rectangular cards -- the shape of a butterfly are interlocked into a hinge. On pulling and releasing strings on both sides the...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>grG2Q8QJDwc</id>
<title><![CDATA[PENCIL BOX PERISCOPE - MARATHI - 14MB]]></title>
<duration>1:43</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is a very clever way of making a simple periscope. Cut the two ends of a cardboard pencil box and attach two plain mirrors at 45-degrees make an improvised periscope. You can sit below...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>7EuwD_CpnqA</id>
<title><![CDATA[SIMPLE SIMart - MARATHI - 11MB]]></title>
<duration>1:31</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[Today everyone has a mobile, debit or a credit card. Cut thin strips from these plastic cards. These strips can be bent, folded and shaped into curves. You can make beautiful artifacts from...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>9wu7Ywv3Y8c</id>
<title><![CDATA[TETRA VOLUME - MARATHI - 17MB]]></title>
<duration>2:13</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[The small fruit juice tetrapak box has a volume of 200-ml. On removing its top it becomes a good cup to measure a volume of 200-ml. The tetrapak cups can be stowed in the shirt pocket and become...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>y6DLYxy8vXY</id>
<title><![CDATA[RING ON WING - MARATHI -  8MB]]></title>
<duration>1:04</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[In this toy a fan made from an old bottle is mounted vertically with magnets. The magnets touch a steel bangle on which is mounted the wire man. When placed under the ceiling fan the spinning...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>miZLLyQZdVE</id>
<title><![CDATA[GEAR MAN -  MARATHI - 6MB]]></title>
<duration>0:51</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[The gears of this toy are plastic lids which mesh beautifully with one another. They are mounted on a frame along with an improvised fan. When placed beneath a ceiling fan the fan spins and...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>KNIC8KVQu_o</id>
<title><![CDATA[30-UNIT BALL -  MARATHI -  21MB]]></title>
<duration>2:42</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make a beautiful paper ball with 30 similar modules folded from paper squares. In this modular origami model each module will fit into the other. The flap of one will fit into the pocket of...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>LQfrkRCQtXs</id>
<title><![CDATA[BALANCING BICYCLE - MARATHI - 11MB]]></title>
<duration>1:29</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[This balancing bicycle is like an acrobat balancing on a tight rope. The heavy weights hanging from the wire loop lowers its center of gravity. The bicycle will stand and remain balanced on...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>u5LxI5NBBPc</id>
<title><![CDATA[PAPER INFLORESCENCE -  MARATHI  - 10MB]]></title>
<duration>1:30</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[Fold 1-cm wide strips into accordion pleats to make a spring. Make a hole in the center and place this spring in a straw. The straw with its zigzag strip will look like a colorful branch. Assemble...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>WGs5oh-YR1Y</id>
<title><![CDATA[FACE FRAUD - MARATHI  - 12MB]]></title>
<duration>1:38</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[Pack a balloon with wheat flour and draw a face on it with a marker. Later, you can squeeze and press the balloon to make the face laugh or cry. You can make dimples on its cheeks by pressing...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>V5uJSSbp0As</id>
<title><![CDATA[BOTTLE BASE SPINNER  - MARATHI - 10MB]]></title>
<duration>1:21</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[Cut the base of the bottle and draw a 5-pointed star pattern with a marker pen. Cut the petals with a scissors. Twist petals to make fan blades. The bottle base has a natural pip -- which makes...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Offm8gX1k4A</id>
<title><![CDATA[TUMBLING CAPSULE -  MARATHI - 6MB]]></title>
<duration>0:57</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[Children have played with this simple toy for many decades. Empty an old medicine capsule and place a steel cycle ball bearing inside it. Place the capsule on one end of a card sheet 'V' channel....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>2GPJQRvjx34</id>
<title><![CDATA[TUMBLING MATCHBOX -  MARATHI  - 17MB]]></title>
<duration>2:22</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[The tumbling toy is based on a traditional toy. Two marbles are placed in an elliptical card box painted on top with a monkey. When placed on an incline the monkey tumbles down the ramp and...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>IxS2GnYFygY</id>
<title><![CDATA[MOTHER AND CHILD - MARATHI - 8MB]]></title>
<duration>1:10</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is very beautiful and sensitive 3-D picture of a mother hugging her child. It looks as if the mother is embracing the child. You can rotate it and admire this beautiful 3-D paper sculptor...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>s8JG2lDkODc</id>
<title><![CDATA[FLAPPING WINGS  - MARATHI  - 10MB]]></title>
<duration>1:19</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[All you need to make this toy is card sheet, wire; old ball pen refills straws and other simple materials. The flapping wing toy is based on the principle of the CRANK. The crank converts...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>1VjCrNSjG0s</id>
<title><![CDATA[COLOR FILTER - MARATHI -  21MB]]></title>
<duration>1:35</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make a dilute solution of potassium permagnate and sodium hydroxide. The solution will look pink. Pass this solution through four layers of filter paper. The solution which will come out will...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>kirVHyikLcA</id>
<title><![CDATA[BALANCING DOLL - MARATHI - 5MB]]></title>
<duration>1:00</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[This Balancing Doll is intriguing and you can play with it for long hours. The doll's pivot is perched on a wooden tripod. Its long arms extend down and have wooden blocks for hands. This lowers...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>qGGQr261zrg</id>
<title><![CDATA[SHIMMERING BIRD - MARATHI - 15MB]]></title>
<duration>1:52</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[When you let this card sheet bird go off a taut thread it comes down in short funny jerks. The bird falls because of its weight but the friction between the refill and the thread slows it....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>0aoHxM6e_Kw</id>
<title><![CDATA[LABORING MAN -  MARATHI  - 19MB]]></title>
<duration>2:23</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[This model of the Laboring Man uses a lot of mechanical contraptions -- and all of them use throwaway cardboard, refills, wire etc. As you rotate the pinion-axle the platform will move and...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>ebR6D21QBhQ</id>
<title><![CDATA[BOTTLE TORNADO - MARATHI - 17MB]]></title>
<duration>1:17</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[Normally you blow a balloon with your mouth. However it is great fun to blow a balloon inside a bottle. Make a small hole in the cylindrical surface near the base in a 2-litre bottle. Glue...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>undJJrT5g-s</id>
<title><![CDATA[PLAY ROUNDABOUT -  MARATHI - 9MB]]></title>
<duration>1:02</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[This round-about swing is made from paper cups, skewers, tape, straws and other odd things. When you give the roundabout a twirl it spins smoothly. On placing it under the ceiling fan the roundabou...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DckOcXuyygM</id>
<title><![CDATA[SILVER TREE - MARATHI - 8MB]]></title>
<duration>1:16</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[Dip a clean copper rod in Silver Nitrate solution. You will soon see a silver deposit on the copper rod. On removing the rod you will find it coated with silver. Now cut a copper foil into...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>LH0K6Rwn-WU</id>
<title><![CDATA[VACUUM SUCTION  - MARATHI - 16MB]]></title>
<duration>2:02</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[As a cut bottle is inverted over a burning candle it consumes oxygen. This creates a partial vacuum and sucks water and raises the level in the middle bottle. http://arvindguptatoys.com/toys/Vacuu...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>TQtgEwbGbC4</id>
<title><![CDATA[PAPER STATIC -  MARATHI - 10MB]]></title>
<duration>1:29</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[Stand a pointed pencil in a cup. Fold a plus sign in a rectangular strip of paper and perch it on the pencil tip. Rub a plastic straw a few times with tissue paper to electrically charge it!...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>pjNhqVne03U</id>
<title><![CDATA[LIGHT A L. E. D. -  MARATHI - 9MB]]></title>
<duration>1:09</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[Attach the terminals of a 6-volt DC toy motor to a LED. Press fit a small pulley to the motor shaft. On flicking the pulley the motor will act like a generator and will light up a LED. Mount...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>0YngcRSdfM0</id>
<title><![CDATA[STIRLING ENGINE - MARATHI -  26MB]]></title>
<duration>2:52</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[This Stirling Engine has been designed by Subir Bhaduri. The wooden box houses all the various parts of the engine and also forms its base. Most of the moving parts have been salvaged from...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>D3yNONqKt0g</id>
<title><![CDATA[WRITING WITH WATER -  MARATHI - 8MB]]></title>
<duration>1:21</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[You can literally write with water. Soak some filter papers in the pink solution of cobalt chloride and then dry them in the sun. The dry filter papers will look bluish. Write on the blue filter...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>J3l1X5rFlvM</id>
<title><![CDATA[YEN FOR YELLOW - MARATHI - 8MB]]></title>
<duration>1:18</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[Place a little Lead Nitrate and Potassium Iodide in two different cups. Add water and stir well. Now add one solution to the other. Surprisingly the colorless liquids will turn a bright yellow....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>rQHuUbOIGbk</id>
<title><![CDATA[FLYING COLOR -  MARATHI - 13MB]]></title>
<duration>1:49</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[Dip a clean copper rod in Silver Nitrate solution. You will soon see a silver deposit on the copper rod. On removing the rod you will find it coated with silver. Now cut a copper foil into...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>qbxzYebfF1w</id>
<title><![CDATA[MERRY GO ROUND -  MARATHI - 11MB]]></title>
<duration>1:16</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[This Merry Go Round is made from all kinds of odd things. The basic swing is made from wire, sleeve and the seat is made from corrugated plastic sheet. Make 8 such swings and hang them from...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>muUiEGSX-oA</id>
<title><![CDATA[COKE CAN AEROPLANE -  MARATHI - 7MB]]></title>
<duration>1:00</duration>
<date>2013-10-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[With throwaway Aluminum cans, bottle caps and cycle spokes you can make a colorful airplane. It cost very little and is great fun to make. The under-carriage is made from a bent cycle spoke....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Tw0raYxwx_8</id>
<title><![CDATA[BUBBLING UP - MARATHI - 16MB]]></title>
<duration>1:48</duration>
<date>2013-10-02</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make a hole in the base of a thin plastic glass. Shut the hole with your finger and then push the glass inside a fish tank full of water. The glass will stick to the base of the tank like a...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>81zXz-vDd60</id>
<title><![CDATA[CORRUGATED CAR - MARATHI - 15MB]]></title>
<duration>1:52</duration>
<date>2013-10-02</date>
<description><![CDATA[Peel the outer layer of a corrugated card sheet to expose the corrugations. Cut a car with wheels and windows. Glue it to a frame to make a very elegant 3-D artifact. This is truly ART from...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>WZxhPfK4DsE</id>
<title><![CDATA[SUN FACE - MARATHI - 15MB]]></title>
<duration>1:25</duration>
<date>2013-10-02</date>
<description><![CDATA[You can make a beautiful artifact from a throwaway aluminum foil plate. The face looks extremely elegant both from the front and the back. This is truly ART from TRASH. http://arvindguptatoys.com/t...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>vu4_WrWEfJI</id>
<title><![CDATA[SPINNING FLAGS - MARATHI - 14MB]]></title>
<duration>2:04</duration>
<date>2013-10-02</date>
<description><![CDATA[Four card flags are attached to stiff straws. All of them are mounted on a cycle spoke. As you hold the model under a ceiling fan all the 4 flags rotate in different directions, depending on...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>xHE0SL5pV8I</id>
<title><![CDATA[BISCUIT PACKET CLOSURE - MARATHI - 9MB]]></title>
<duration>1:09</duration>
<date>2013-10-02</date>
<description><![CDATA[Here is a neat way of closing and sealing an open biscuit packet such that the remaining biscuits do not get soiled and remain fresh. http://arvindguptatoys.com/toys/Biscuitpacketclosure.html.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>lquZuQsFZ9Q</id>
<title><![CDATA[TWO BLADE FAN - MARATHI - 9MB]]></title>
<duration>1:16</duration>
<date>2013-10-02</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is a wonderful fan propeller made in a jiffy using a rectangular strip of card. The fan is perched on a ball pen refill and spins very fast under a ceiling fan. http://arvindguptatoys.com/toy...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>HTlDk4JyhsA</id>
<title><![CDATA[LOOPS TO SQUARE - MARATHI - 17MB]]></title>
<duration>2:13</duration>
<date>2013-10-02</date>
<description><![CDATA[Stick two paper loops at right angles to each other. On cutting them the first time you will get a handcuff -- a strip joining two loops. On cutting the strip of the handcuff you will get a...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>qJJfCAppB_s</id>
<title><![CDATA[MAGNETIC TO AND FRO - MARATHI - 16MB]]></title>
<duration>2:33</duration>
<date>2013-10-02</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is an amazing magnetic toy where a ring magnet flips sides and keeps continuously travelling from left to right. http://arvindguptatoys.com/toys/Magnetictoandfro.html.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>utbYB9McDTM</id>
<title><![CDATA[NAME PLATE - MARATHI - 25MB]]></title>
<duration>2:46</duration>
<date>2013-10-02</date>
<description><![CDATA[From a rectangular strip of paper (length should be thrice the width) you can fold a very elegant prismatic tent like Name Plate which you can place on your table http://arvindguptatoys.com/toys/N...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>4dMpuVTtNN8</id>
<title><![CDATA[ANGLES OF A CHORD - MARATHI - 22MB]]></title>
<duration>2:47</duration>
<date>2013-10-02</date>
<description><![CDATA[This practical experiment demonstrates that the various angles made on a chord of a circle measure the same. http://arvindguptatoys.com/toys/Inscribedanglesofachord.html.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>ySC09Wz_dqs</id>
<title><![CDATA[MAGICAL FLIP FLOP - MARATHI - 15MB]]></title>
<duration>1:44</duration>
<date>2013-10-02</date>
<description><![CDATA[Made from a square paper this magical flip-flop switches from left to right as you open and close it. http://arvindguptatoys.com/toys/Magicalflip-flop.html.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>I5I2yIPslu8</id>
<title><![CDATA[BALLOON BUGLE - MARATHI - 17MB]]></title>
<duration>2:01</duration>
<date>2013-10-02</date>
<description><![CDATA[Cut a hole in a balloon. Stretch the hole on the mouth of a plastic cut bottle 10-cm high. Fix a card reel in the mouth of the balloon. On blowing through the reel the bugle will make a trumpet...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>ClrW14prbGY</id>
<title><![CDATA[FANTASTIC FAN - MARATHI - 16MB]]></title>
<duration>2:04</duration>
<date>2013-10-01</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make a propeller from a stiff card circle and mount it on a wire axle. Tape the wire end to a bent straw. On blowing from the other end of the straw the fan will spin at a fantastic speed!...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>PPXVUQG51t0</id>
<title><![CDATA[STRIKING SWAN - MARATHI - 14MB]]></title>
<duration>1:58</duration>
<date>2013-10-01</date>
<description><![CDATA[The heart of this toy is a wire crank. As you rotate the crank the swan moves its neck and strikes in a very imposing way. http://arvindguptatoys.com/toys/Strikingswan.html.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>mXUEFIXMsyA</id>
<title><![CDATA[BALL ILLUSION -  MARATHI - 15MB]]></title>
<duration>2:21</duration>
<date>2013-10-01</date>
<description><![CDATA[A color plastic ball is inserted in a stiff wire spiral. As the spiral rotates in one direction the ball appears to go up. When the spiral rotates in the other direction the ball seems to be...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>tnZIfFZlIIU</id>
<title><![CDATA[DEAR DEER - MARATHI - 15MB]]></title>
<duration>1:59</duration>
<date>2013-10-01</date>
<description><![CDATA[With 5 soft PIPE CLEANERS you can make a very pretty deer. http://arvindguptatoys.com/toys/Deardeer0.html.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>sCnpYhEXDs4</id>
<title><![CDATA[COLOUR CHROMA - MARATHI - 21MB]]></title>
<duration>2:46</duration>
<date>2013-10-01</date>
<description><![CDATA[See how colors separate because of dispersion -- the molecules of different colors moving at different speeds. The process of Chromatography is often used to separate mixtures in laboratories....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>nPqCE-Ogirc</id>
<title><![CDATA[PRETTY PETALS - MARATHI - 23MB]]></title>
<duration>2:59</duration>
<date>2013-10-01</date>
<description><![CDATA[With the bases of two throwaway paper cups make these exquisite Petals. This is truly ART from TRASH! http://arvindguptatoys.com/toys/Prettypetals.html.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>7oZs1WCnRzY</id>
<title><![CDATA[FLICK A BALL - MARATHI - 11MB]]></title>
<duration>1:39</duration>
<date>2013-10-01</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is an interesting experiment which demonstrates the inertia of a body. A ball is placed on a card sheet. The card sheet is placed on an inverted cup. On flicking the card flies off but...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>K9dyZPT4fPM</id>
<title><![CDATA[BALL TRAMPOLINE - MARATHI - 13MB]]></title>
<duration>2:04</duration>
<date>2013-10-01</date>
<description><![CDATA[Cut a good quality balloon and stretch its lower end on a stiff plastic cup. The stretched membrane will act like a trampoline. Now drop a cycle ball from a height of 10-cm. The ball will strike...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>AcYJf81wALQ</id>
<title><![CDATA[STRIKING BIRD - MARATHI - 16MB]]></title>
<duration>2:17</duration>
<date>2013-10-01</date>
<description><![CDATA[This beautiful dynamic moving bird is made using 2-cm long straw joints and five coffee stirrers. The coffee stirrers go snugly in the straw joints. On holding the two legs of the bird and...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>yxxekL7bur8</id>
<title><![CDATA[NODES AND ANTINODES - MARATHI - 11MB]]></title>
<duration>1:41</duration>
<date>2013-10-01</date>
<description><![CDATA[Hang 40-cm long wool from a toy motor. Tie a cycle hex nut to the end. Switch ON the motor to see beautiful nodes and antinodes in the spinning wool. Change the motor speed and the hanging...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>EEU4y-vD0hw</id>
<title><![CDATA[CENTRIFUGE SPRINKLER - MARATHI - 25MB]]></title>
<duration>2:28</duration>
<date>2013-10-01</date>
<description><![CDATA[Place two slant straws in 8-cm high cut 2-litre plastic bottle. Hang the bottle by a long thread. Twist the thread completely by spinning the bottle. Then fill it 3/4ths with water. Then let...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>nFHIcF_ggOM</id>
<title><![CDATA[PAPER ROTOCOPTER - MARATHI - 18MB]]></title>
<duration>2:30</duration>
<date>2013-10-01</date>
<description><![CDATA[A very wonderful way of measuring the number of rotations of a paper helicopter is by attaching a 2-meter long audio cassette magnetic tape. The twists measure the exact number of rotations....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Y8gFxl20KMI</id>
<title><![CDATA[SHIMMERING BUTTERFLY - MARATHI - 20MB]]></title>
<duration>2:29</duration>
<date>2013-10-01</date>
<description><![CDATA[As the five ring magnets spin and descend on a fat spoke the butterfly attached to a paper clips comes shimmering down. This is a very beautiful magnetic toy. http://arvindguptatoys.com/toys/Shimme...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>a-oU9V2CqXo</id>
<title><![CDATA[SQUARE PAPER TOP - MARATHI - 24MB]]></title>
<duration>2:54</duration>
<date>2013-10-01</date>
<description><![CDATA[Fold a 15-cm stiff paper into a square and push half a tooth pick in the middle for the axle. On spinning the tooth pick the top will keep spinning for a long time. No glue is needed to make...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>ThEmrFE_bYc</id>
<title><![CDATA[RIGHT ANGLE DRIVE - MARATHI - 16MB]]></title>
<duration>2:16</duration>
<date>2013-09-27</date>
<description><![CDATA[This simple toy demonstrates transmission of drive at right angles. http://arvindguptatoys.com/toys/Rightangledrive.html.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>PQoPhunKjHg</id>
<title><![CDATA[SPINNING BALLOON - MARATHI - 14MB]]></title>
<duration>1:47</duration>
<date>2013-09-27</date>
<description><![CDATA[A straw is pivoted on a pin in the center and can spin on a refill. Attach a balloon on one end and inflate it from the other end of the straw. As the balloon deflates air will gust out of...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>OWI9RnmeTwc</id>
<title><![CDATA[GLASS CENTRIFUGE - MARATHI - 20MB]]></title>
<duration>2:00</duration>
<date>2013-09-27</date>
<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>2mTsVhqT7oE</id>
<title><![CDATA[SPIN WATER MAKE PARABOLA - MARATHI - 17MB]]></title>
<duration>1:45</duration>
<date>2013-09-27</date>
<description><![CDATA[Suspend a cup half filled with water with threads. Twist the threads. On leaving the cup it will spin and because of centrifugal force water will climb up the walls of the cup and make a bowl....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>W5ubQaaMuL4</id>
<title><![CDATA[PEN SPINNER - MARATHI - 16MB]]></title>
<duration>1:57</duration>
<date>2013-09-27</date>
<description><![CDATA[As you blow from the back of an old sketch pen body the air gushes out of the three nozzles and spins a card propeller. http://www.arvindguptatoys.com/toys/Penspinner.html.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Gmx4VGWCQjk</id>
<title><![CDATA[MAGNETIC HOPPING -  MARATHI - 20MB]]></title>
<duration>2:39</duration>
<date>2013-09-27</date>
<description><![CDATA[As you move the bug on the plastic scale with magnets stuck below the bug jumps and falls - in a hopping motion. A very endearing magnetic toy.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>1v3LkZZSUzc</id>
<title><![CDATA[SOFT SPIDER - MARATHI - 18MB]]></title>
<duration>2:05</duration>
<date>2013-09-27</date>
<description><![CDATA[This cuddly soft spider is made from 6 pipe cleaners. The two long pipe cleaners make the figure of eight body of the spider and the others make legs. It is wonderful piece of art. http://www.arvin...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>iF-16n7TcHA</id>
<title><![CDATA[FOUR BLADE FAN - MARATHI - 16MB]]></title>
<duration>2:00</duration>
<date>2013-09-27</date>
<description><![CDATA[Here is a very simple way of making a delightful fan. All you need is a few strips of paper, a press button and a fat straw. The fan axis is perched on the press button. This reduces friction....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>CwgVGrnocH8</id>
<title><![CDATA[SAFETY PIN SPINNER - MARATHI - 20MB]]></title>
<duration>2:50</duration>
<date>2013-09-27</date>
<description><![CDATA[A wonderful balancing toy made by pivoting two large safety pins and hanging cycle nuts to lower their center of gravity. Attach card sheet paddles to act as fan blades. This toy when placed...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>biBqOOxlSOo</id>
<title><![CDATA[SPIRAL MOTION - MARATHI - 23MB]]></title>
<duration>2:50</duration>
<date>2013-09-27</date>
<description><![CDATA[Take 40-cm of plastic book binding spiral. Place long safety pins, a wire loop or a color CD in this spiral. They all will come spiraling down and look amazingly beautiful! http://arvindguptatoys.c...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>X5xon0OgiA8</id>
<title><![CDATA[OPTICAL PATTERNS - MARATHI - 33MB]]></title>
<duration>2:58</duration>
<date>2013-09-27</date>
<description><![CDATA[Take printouts on transparency of three different patterns -- radial, spiral and wavelike. As you move one radial pattern on the other you will see amazing Moiré Patterns -- like the patterns...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>SpqpdSY3ADA</id>
<title><![CDATA[CLIMBING FUNNELS - MARATHI - 13MB]]></title>
<duration>2:11</duration>
<date>2013-09-27</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is an apparent paradox -- how can something climb uphill? However, when two funnels are stuck on their rims the shape is quite unique. When placed on the lower end of a ramp their center...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>wyfNC55joSc</id>
<title><![CDATA[FLIP IT! MOON - MARATHI - 16MB]]></title>
<duration>1:58</duration>
<date>2013-09-27</date>
<description><![CDATA[Take two printouts -- cut 28 rectangular strips and staple them to make a Flip Book. As you flip this book you can see the moon waxing and waning -- starting from a No-Moon night the size of...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>m25z5qWtNsw</id>
<title><![CDATA[ROARING BOTTLE - MARATHI - 16MB]]></title>
<duration>1:56</duration>
<date>2013-09-27</date>
<description><![CDATA[An amazing sound toy made entirely out of junk. Push two different size lids with holes into each other. Push a wooden stick through the holes. Cut a bottle 2/3rds from the base. Discard the...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>xV6OIxW05qg</id>
<title><![CDATA[LUTE FLUTE - MARATHI - 9MB]]></title>
<duration>1:10</duration>
<date>2013-09-27</date>
<description><![CDATA[This wooden flute has no holes to play notes. Instead a snug piston can move inside-out from the other end. Blow from the flute end to produce sound and then move the piston inside-out to make...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>530dfIuufmw</id>
<title><![CDATA[PHASES OF MOON - MARATHI - 19MB]]></title>
<duration>2:21</duration>
<date>2013-09-27</date>
<description><![CDATA[The waxing and waning of the moon has been observed for millennia. This simple model shows how the Full Moon goes from gibbous to half, to crescent and to the New Moon. The visual clues will...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>MOxawIfmvvU</id>
<title><![CDATA[QUICK ADDITION - MARATHI - 11MB]]></title>
<duration>1:46</duration>
<date>2013-09-16</date>
<description><![CDATA[Fredrick Gauss -- on whom the 'Bell-shaped Gaussian Curve' is named, was a child prodigy. It is important in science and mathematics not to do things mechanically but to look at patterns. This...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>311HvUa1li8</id>
<title><![CDATA[FUN FRACTION - MARATHI - 25MB]]></title>
<duration>3:02</duration>
<date>2013-09-16</date>
<description><![CDATA[A bookish problem can be converted into a practical problem. A farmer has a field measuring 2 and 2/3 acres. He wishes to sell 1 Acre of his land. The given rectangular piece of paper is equivalent...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>brXQxVMi9K0</id>
<title><![CDATA[THROBBING HEART - MARATHI - 18MB]]></title>
<duration>2:11</duration>
<date>2013-09-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[Fold a heart from a square paper. Hold the triangle from behind and move your thumb and index finger to make it throb.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>m56NN9jOXUc</id>
<title><![CDATA[PUSH BOX - MARATHI - 31MB]]></title>
<duration>3:33</duration>
<date>2013-09-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[Fold a rectangular piece of paper to make a magical push-pull box. On pulling it becomes a rectangular strip and on pushing it becomes a box.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>aHzBj70Kpz8</id>
<title><![CDATA[STRIP TO CIRCLE - MARATHI - 27MB]]></title>
<duration>3:15</duration>
<date>2013-08-29</date>
<description><![CDATA[Fold a circle from a rectangular strip of paper. You can make a very beautiful circular motif using this technique. Tracing paper will enable you to see the creases very clearly.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>yg5h4rC62Mg</id>
<title><![CDATA[TWO SQUARE TETRA - MARATHI - 20MB]]></title>
<duration>2:12</duration>
<date>2013-08-29</date>
<description><![CDATA[Fold two squares into simple modules and then assemble them to make this amazing tetrahedron. You will not need any glue or scissors.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DmN6VCSjr0Q</id>
<title><![CDATA[RECTANGULAR PAPER BOX - MARATHI - 26MB]]></title>
<duration>2:56</duration>
<date>2013-08-29</date>
<description><![CDATA[Fold a beautiful Rectangular box from a square piece of paper. You will not need any glue or scissors.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>IhyKi0-9XGg</id>
<title><![CDATA[IRREGULAR PAPER REGULAR RECTANGLE - MARATHI - 24MB]]></title>
<duration>2:31</duration>
<date>2013-08-29</date>
<description><![CDATA[This video will show you how to fold a Regular Rectangle from an irregular piece of paper.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>ixQD3pmvNSM</id>
<title><![CDATA[IRREGULAR PAPER REGULAR PARALLELOGRAM - MARATHI - 25MB]]></title>
<duration>2:37</duration>
<date>2013-08-29</date>
<description><![CDATA[This video will show you how to fold a Regular Parallelogram from an irregular piece of paper.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>NZFLZzDGieo</id>
<title><![CDATA[PAPER TUMBLER - MARATHI - 16MB]]></title>
<duration>2:08</duration>
<date>2013-07-25</date>
<description><![CDATA[Fold a 15-cm stiff paper square into a dynamic tumbling toy. Place this U shaped paper toy on the table with the heavy part on the top. On pushing it a little it will make a forward roll!]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>_yNSbVcKStc</id>
<title><![CDATA[20-TWENTY SET SQUARE - MARATHI - 22MB]]></title>
<duration>3:07</duration>
<date>2013-07-25</date>
<description><![CDATA[Fold an angle measuring Set Square from a 20-cm paper square. Start by folding a 20-degree angle and then fold 15 other angles. A very handy way to measure and estimate angles!]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>OL_sPP4SF_8</id>
<title><![CDATA[PAPER FROG - MARATHI - 21MB]]></title>
<duration>2:33</duration>
<date>2013-07-25</date>
<description><![CDATA[This paper frog folded from a stiff square has a Z shaped spring and a big mouth! Place it on a table and on pressing the spring the frog will jump and leap forwards!]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>qWvd-glPy7Y</id>
<title><![CDATA[CURIOUS RAT - MARATHI  - 11MB]]></title>
<duration>1:20</duration>
<date>2013-07-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[Fold a 15-cm square of paper into a CURIOUS RAT. The folds are simple and painting the eyes make the rat looks prettier. Hold the tail with your thumb and index finger. On rubbing the tail...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>cQ_mNL5N72o</id>
<title><![CDATA[PAPER WOODPECKER - MARATHI - 16MB]]></title>
<duration>1:58</duration>
<date>2013-07-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[Fold a 20-cm square of paper into a dynamic moving woodpecker. As you hold the base and press the top end the woodpecker pecks at the tree trunk.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>5ac9DZGnaDk</id>
<title><![CDATA[ROLL AND WALK  -  MARATHI -19MB]]></title>
<duration>2:20</duration>
<date>2013-07-20</date>
<description><![CDATA[As a small cylinder rolls the two cranks attached to it move two slippers. The model is fascinating as you can see two slippers going left, right, left right .... http://arvindguptatoys.com/toys/Ro...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>p_2Rwv2hKkk</id>
<title><![CDATA[RUB AND DANCE - MARATHI - 13MB]]></title>
<duration>1:48</duration>
<date>2013-07-18</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make a 5-cm diameter ring from a soft pipe cleaner. Mount a Wireman diametrically on the soft ring. Staple a dozen staples on a paper cup to make a ladder. Place ring with Wireman on the inverted...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>9BXGUf2pZAY</id>
<title><![CDATA[KALEIDOSCOPE MAGIC - MARATHI - 21MB]]></title>
<duration>2:24</duration>
<date>2013-07-18</date>
<description><![CDATA[Stick three trapezoidal strips of mirrors in the shape of a prism. This taper prism will have a small triangle on one end and a big triangle on the other end. On placing the Kaleidoscope on...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>ZzEwZr01nTA</id>
<title><![CDATA[DROP BY DROP - MARATHI - 26MB]]></title>
<duration>2:58</duration>
<date>2013-05-06</date>
<description><![CDATA[Stick two bottle lids and insert two short straws in the lids. Attach two bottle filled with Kerosene and Water to the two lids. Stand the bottles with the Kerosene below. Water and Kerosene...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>ZPapqcFJVhI</id>
<title><![CDATA[AUTO-SIPHON - MARATHI - 13MB]]></title>
<duration>1:35</duration>
<date>2013-05-06</date>
<description><![CDATA[Bend an aluminum wire to make a tall and short hill. The end of the tall hill should be long and the short hill should be short. Tape a flexi-plastic tube to the wire. The tube will remain...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>ii_9tvQvUnY</id>
<title><![CDATA[SHRINK AND SINK - MARATHI - 14MB]]></title>
<duration>2:00</duration>
<date>2013-05-06</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is a new kind of Cartesian diver. Fill some ball bearings in a balloon to make it heavy. Inflate a little air and then tie its mouth. The balloon must just float in a mug of water. Then...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>TvXLBhtjL0c</id>
<title><![CDATA[SYRINGE BOTTLE PUMP - MARATHI - 18MB]]></title>
<duration>2:09</duration>
<date>2013-05-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[A very efficient pump made from a 20-ml plastic syringe and a small plastic bottle. The syringe makes an excellent cylinder-piston. A flap in the bottle lid acts as the 'suction valve' and...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>nlUlSdbmq48</id>
<title><![CDATA[THREE BOTTLE FOUNTAIN - MARATHI - 39MB]]></title>
<duration>4:02</duration>
<date>2013-04-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[Plastic bottles are aplenty today. With three plastic bottles, a stiff straw and two flexi-tubes you can easily make the famous Heron's Fountain. Water from the top (cut) bottle enters the...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>X632ccSZC7s</id>
<title><![CDATA[AMMONIA FOUNTAIN - MARATHI - 14MB]]></title>
<duration>1:52</duration>
<date>2013-04-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[Heat Ammonium Hydroxide in a test tube and collect the Ammonia gas in a flask. Press fit a double holed cork in the flask. The cork has two droppers -- one is attached to a rubber bulb. The...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>X9E9mbcE75c</id>
<title><![CDATA[BALLOON BOTTLE FOUNTAIN - MARATHI - 16MB]]></title>
<duration>2:09</duration>
<date>2013-04-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[Press fit a stiff straw near the base of a stiff plastic bottle. Now place a balloon in the bottle and stretch its mouth on the bottle. On sucking from the stiff straw the balloon will inflate...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>YhKrGKE1z6A</id>
<title><![CDATA[PALS CLIMB PEAKS - MARATHI - 20MB]]></title>
<duration>3:15</duration>
<date>2013-04-19</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is an amazing story of four friends that go trekking on nearby hills. The story is told using just three paper cups, for hills and four buttons, for friends. It is fascinating to watch...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Aqf8FrQnlFs</id>
<title><![CDATA[EDDY CURRENT BRAKE - MARATHI - 14MB]]></title>
<duration>1:57</duration>
<date>2013-04-09</date>
<description><![CDATA[Bring two Neodymium Magnets close a spinning Aluminum Plate without touching it. The strong magnets will generate Eddy Currents in the Aluminum Plate because of which it will slowly brake and...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>OiflfDM97rM</id>
<title><![CDATA[BOTTLE SHOWER - MARATHI - 11MB]]></title>
<duration>1:28</duration>
<date>2013-04-09</date>
<description><![CDATA[Fill a bottle with color water. Make a small hole in its lid and shut it on the bottle. Make a few holes near the base of the bottle with a thumb tack. On opening the lid hole a water shower...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>bmWydUTKyEk</id>
<title><![CDATA[VACUUM SUCTION - MARATHI - 16MB]]></title>
<duration>2:02</duration>
<date>2013-04-08</date>
<description><![CDATA[As a cut bottle is inverted over a burning candle it consumes oxygen. This creates a partial vacuum and sucks water and raises the level in the middle bottle. http://arvindguptatoys.com/toys/Vacuu...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>lbwMFblPYkg</id>
<title><![CDATA[CRANKY SKIPPER - MARATHI - 9MB]]></title>
<duration>1:19</duration>
<date>2013-04-08</date>
<description><![CDATA[This wonderful boy keeps skipping a rope. The boy is made from a throwaway plastic bottle and is mounted on a loop of wire which ends into a crank. As you rotate the wire handle the boy skips...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>_Mf893JBHAM</id>
<title><![CDATA[REDUCE VOLUME INCREASE DENSITY - MARATHI - 9MB]]></title>
<duration>1:21</duration>
<date>2013-04-08</date>
<description><![CDATA[Fill smoke from an incense stick in the glass barrel of a 20-ml syringe. Now shut the outlet and push in the plunger. The smoke will now be pushed into a small volume -- its density will increase...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>08xfs_Evzok</id>
<title><![CDATA[FIERY FOUNTAIN - MARATHI - 11MB]]></title>
<duration>1:35</duration>
<date>2013-04-08</date>
<description><![CDATA[As a candle burns in a shut jam jar it consumes the oxygen contained in it. This creates a partial vacuum and the color water gushes through a dropper nozzle like a fountain. http://arvindguptatoys...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>h_4O0wu4s1k</id>
<title><![CDATA[DYNAMIC WAVE MODEL - MARATHI - 24MB]]></title>
<duration>2:35</duration>
<date>2013-03-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[Drill 16-equidistant holes on the periphery of two old CDs. Join the CDs with 16 skewers or broom sticks each with a tight fitting bead. Phase out the beads in the form of a sign wave. On...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>itOSSQjZOzc</id>
<title><![CDATA[INDUCED EDDY CURRENT - MARATHI - 22MB]]></title>
<duration>2:51</duration>
<date>2013-03-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is a fine demonstration which illustrates Eddy Currents. Mount a thick walled aluminum can on a needle so that it can spin freely. Spin two Neodymium Magnets and lower them in the aluminum...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>df8hMz-p2Cw</id>
<title><![CDATA[STICK STOOL - MARATHI - 14MB]]></title>
<duration>1:48</duration>
<date>2013-03-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make16-equidistant holes on the periphery of two 10-cm diameter plastic lids. Join the lids with 16 skewers or broomsticks to make a cylindrical cage. On twisting the two lids in opposite...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>hJcym2fS4YY</id>
<title><![CDATA[RESISTENT PENCIL - MARATHI - 19MB]]></title>
<duration>2:24</duration>
<date>2013-03-13</date>
<description><![CDATA[Splice a pencil in half so that its black writing 'lead' is exposed. The lead is made of clay and graphite and has an electrical resistance. Connect a 4.5- Volt batteries and a torch bulb in...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>t6qcHXM6uPw</id>
<title><![CDATA[EDDY CURRENT SPINNER - MARATHI - 27MB]]></title>
<duration>3:00</duration>
<date>2013-03-13</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is a fine experiment to demonstrate Eddy Currents. A bottle with 4 strong neodymium magnets spins because of the ceiling fan breeze. There are two aluminum cans pivots close to the spinning...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>48EfFIjxoqk</id>
<title><![CDATA[MAGNETIC OSILLATIONS - MARATHI - 20MB]]></title>
<duration>2:36</duration>
<date>2013-03-13</date>
<description><![CDATA[In this experiment two coils with 200-turns of insulated copper are joined together. Each coil hangs in a strong neodymium magnet. As you oscillate one coil over the magnet -- an EMF is produced...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>SHpa9i25DeA</id>
<title><![CDATA[MONKEY ACROBAT - MARATHI -13MB]]></title>
<duration>1:32</duration>
<date>2013-03-04</date>
<description><![CDATA[Hang a monkey from a horizontal yellow straw. Attach the spring ends of two blue bendable straws from its ends. Then bend the blue straws at right angles. On twirling the blue straws the horizontal...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>-4LJhGxMHuU</id>
<title><![CDATA[LIGHTHOUSE GENERATOR - MARATHI - 26MB]]></title>
<duration>2:59</duration>
<date>2013-03-04</date>
<description><![CDATA[The Lighthouse Generator is a wonderful scientific model. A pen passes through a 1000-turn coil. The ends are attached to a LED. This pen can spin smoothly between 4 strong neodymium magnets....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>HtYSgK_WlIY</id>
<title><![CDATA[SPLENDID STRAW - MARATHI - 11MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:27</duration>
<date>2013-02-21</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make many small cuts, equally spaced along the length of a good quality color straw. The cut straw will become a long chain with connected beads. Curl, wrap and stick these blue beads on a...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>jxRAySpGt2w</id>
<title><![CDATA[STATIC TISSUE - MARATHI - 13MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:48</duration>
<date>2013-02-21</date>
<description><![CDATA[Static Electricity can become great fun for children with this simple experiment. Cut two fishes from Tissue paper. Rub a plastic scale on a polyester cloth to charge it electrically. The fishes...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>vNiPB0-P6vE</id>
<title><![CDATA[WIND MULTI GENERATOR - MARATHI - 28MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>3:09</duration>
<date>2013-02-06</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is the future of energy -- producing electricity from wind. Four LED's light up as this multi-generator spins. The magnets go past coils with 1000-turns of wire. This produces a small...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>0A0ZKDlHf2U</id>
<title><![CDATA[BOTTLE FAN - MARATHI - 18MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:14</duration>
<date>2013-02-06</date>
<description><![CDATA[With two bottles you can make a very efficient fan. The spinning blades are made from one bottle and the other bottle forms the body. The vertical axle is a cycle spoke which rests inside a...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Vv0QxpIY6pI</id>
<title><![CDATA[STRECH AND JUMP - MARATHI - 20MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:27</duration>
<date>2013-02-06</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is a simple and delightful toy. As you press the card hoop the rubber band inside it is stretched. On releasing the rubber band makes the card jump. Now stick a frog to the card. On pressing...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>AU4llIYVe-I</id>
<title><![CDATA[SOLAR WINDGENERATOR - MARATHI - 12MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:30</duration>
<date>2013-02-06</date>
<description><![CDATA[Wind and Solar are non-polluting and futuristic Energy sources. This video shows a Wind Turbine operated with the help of a Solar Cell. When the model is placed in the sun the solar cell creates...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>QIQVdoIpnb8</id>
<title><![CDATA[DOLL DANCE ON CUP - MARATHI -11MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:27</duration>
<date>2013-02-06</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is a delightful toy which can be made in a jiffy. The legs of a paper doll are pasted on the diametric ends of a bottomless plastic cup. On pressing and releasing the rim the doll moves...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>0OkP8gKOHl0</id>
<title><![CDATA[CUBICAL DANCE - MARATHI - 31MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>3:16</duration>
<date>2013-02-06</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is a very dynamic three-dimensional model of 8 hinged paper cubes. These cubes can rotate and turn easily. The model is quite simple to make. All you need is paper, tape and a scissors....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>BTVKZ_vqlZk</id>
<title><![CDATA[BALANCING PAPER CLIPS - MARATHI -17MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:05</duration>
<date>2013-01-21</date>
<description><![CDATA[Using a few paper clips you can make a wonderful balancing toy. Two paper clips are opened and taped to make two long arms. A few paper clips are hung on each arm hook to lower the center of...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DNIXA4d2ibk</id>
<title><![CDATA[CHEMICAL LIGHT- MARATHI - 9MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:29</duration>
<date>2013-01-21</date>
<description><![CDATA[The heart of this Chemical light is the Light Stick -- used by trekkers to light their tents. These sticks have two liquids -- hydrogen peroxide and luminol. On mixing them in a test tube the...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>97o01xmDLuc</id>
<title><![CDATA[SMOKING KILLS - MARATHI - 16MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:17</duration>
<date>2013-01-21</date>
<description><![CDATA[This simple experiment graphically demonstrates the poisons contained in a cigarette. A cigarette is mounted is a bottle lid. When water drains out it sucks in the cigarette smoke. On passing...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>_dcRbt2W5FM</id>
<title><![CDATA[BRAIN CAP - MARATHI - 19MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:12</duration>
<date>2013-01-21</date>
<description><![CDATA[Inflate a big balloon and stick several layers on newspaper on top to make a papier-mâché cap. Dry it in the sun and trim it. Then paint various parts of the brain -- the frontal, occipital...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>9ltLIAb4hXM</id>
<title><![CDATA[ACROBAT SKELETON - MARATHI - 26MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:52</duration>
<date>2013-01-21</date>
<description><![CDATA[All the bones of the body are made of thick card sheet. The skull and ribcage is doubled. The legs and arms are hinged using a needle-thread. There are knots on both the ends. As you twirl...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>7rLFnhQagsw</id>
<title><![CDATA[MODEL OF A NEURON - MARATHI - 9MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:13</duration>
<date>2013-01-21</date>
<description><![CDATA[Using colorful bright plastic beads you can make a 3-D model of the neuron. The central core or Soma is made out of green beads. The dendrites from pink and the axon chain are made from orange...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Bau2qT4JRwk</id>
<title><![CDATA[EXPANSION OF AIR - MARATHI - 13MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:00</duration>
<date>2012-12-26</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is a crude thermometer. A stiff plastic bottle has a straw which dips in color water. Gently place warm palms on the bottle. DO NOT PRESS. Air will expand and water will climb up the straw....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>SYQbQvn8Rsc</id>
<title><![CDATA[BALANCING BUTTERFLY - MARATHI -  12MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:31</duration>
<date>2012-12-26</date>
<description><![CDATA[The butterfly is cut from a thin card sheet and colored with crayons. Take a matchstick and cut its head. Stick this headless matchstick on the backside. Weigh the front wings with paper clips...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>AaGVuQgL4Go</id>
<title><![CDATA[DANCING DRAGONFLY - MARATHI - 16MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:01</duration>
<date>2012-12-26</date>
<description><![CDATA[This Dragonfly has two parts made from card sheet - the wings and the central body. Stick the wings near the big eyes of the Dragonfly. Curl its tail and bend its nose. Weight the upper wings...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>pGeTjJcyAiU</id>
<title><![CDATA[BALANCING JOKER - MARATHI - 13MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:41</duration>
<date>2012-12-18</date>
<description><![CDATA[This Joker is made from junk and other odd things. It can be pivoted on the finger or on a bottle top. Its long heavy arms lower its center of gravity. On giving it a push the Joker rocks and...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Oiv0FoCGwIE</id>
<title><![CDATA[BALANCING BIRD - MARATHI - 12MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:42</duration>
<date>2012-12-18</date>
<description><![CDATA[Toucans are birds native to Central America. They are colorful with unusually bulky beaks. Draw a toucan on a thick card sheet. Try balancing it on your finger and it will fall. Place a few...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>QdQLb5pxegA</id>
<title><![CDATA[FLUTTERING BUTTERFLY - MARATHI - 15MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:57</duration>
<date>2012-12-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[This model is a very good example of Art from Trash. Take a thin and long transparency strip. Stick a colorful paper butterfly on one end. The other end is taped to the base of an old CD. The...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>WNoH14dmFf4</id>
<title><![CDATA[SPIN FUN - MARATHI - 16MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:57</duration>
<date>2012-12-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[This spinner is made from a 5-cm stiff card square. There are patterns drawn on this card which can be cut in many different ways to make spinners. They need to cut symmetrically. A half bead...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Gqyb6hrqX4E</id>
<title><![CDATA[CD-PROTRACTOR - MARATHI -17MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:17</duration>
<date>2012-12-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is a genuinely original idea. Stick a printout of a Protractor on an old CD. With this improvised protractor you can measure angles from zero to 360-degrees. This brilliant idea was shared...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>jTF1p8LCMoI</id>
<title><![CDATA[ALUMINUM CAN BOWL - MARATHI -19MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:52</duration>
<date>2012-12-10</date>
<description><![CDATA[From a throwaway aluminum can you can make a beautiful bowl. Cut many parallel strips in a can and then bend them to make the rim of the bowl. This bowl can be used to store lots of small trinkets...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>PWPIwyO6Q6s</id>
<title><![CDATA[TETRA PURSE - MARATHI - 17MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:46</duration>
<date>2012-12-10</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make a wonderful purse from a throwaway tetrapak. The walls of the tetrapak are tucked inside to give it depth. The tetrapak is folded in half and stapled to make the purse. This purse has...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>oSmxdF-gIiY</id>
<title><![CDATA[SYNTHETIC JELLY - MARATHI - 15MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:57</duration>
<date>2012-12-10</date>
<description><![CDATA[Mix borax and synthetic glue with a little bit of water in a bowl. Add some food color. Soon the borax will make a cross-linked polymer and the mixture will soon turn into a semi-solid gel....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>iyyLPDd9CbM</id>
<title><![CDATA[WAVES WITH BALLS - MARATHI - 13MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:39</duration>
<date>2012-12-10</date>
<description><![CDATA[Hang 15 crazy balls having different lengths of thread from a horizontal bar. Push the balls together with the help of a scale. They will swing in a rhythm. The balls will execute a very beautiful...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>UkrjzIIgK5Y</id>
<title><![CDATA[KINETIC HORSE - MARATHI- 12MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:32</duration>
<date>2012-11-29</date>
<description><![CDATA[This Kinetic or Galloping Horse is essentially a modular toy. It's made of straws, rivets and stiff joining straws. On rotating the crank the horse majestically gallops forwards. http://www.arvindg...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Kpmqmm2FLwA</id>
<title><![CDATA[WHEEL GYRO - MARATHI - 10MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:45</duration>
<date>2012-11-29</date>
<description><![CDATA[Two long and strong strings are tied to both ends of a cycle wheel axle. Lift and spin the wheel. Then drop the left string. The spinning wheel not fall but will start rotating in the clockwise...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>6IAz9TnxwR8</id>
<title><![CDATA[BIRDS OF PARADISE - MARATHI - 11MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:36</duration>
<date>2012-11-29</date>
<description><![CDATA[Tie a knot in a long strip of colored paper. The middle part will be a regular pentagon. Make a beak and tail on the two ends of the strip. Weave several such birds with needle and thread and...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>NeF3UMAR4mM</id>
<title><![CDATA[MAGLEV TRAIN - MARATHI - 16MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:13</duration>
<date>2012-11-29</date>
<description><![CDATA[The maglev train was designed by LG of Korea as a readymade science kit. Both the track and the underside of the train have flexi-magnets which repel and levitate the train. An electric motor...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>eKMPtLK5hqk</id>
<title><![CDATA[STRIP PATTERNS - MARATHI - 10MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:20</duration>
<date>2012-11-29</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make a flower shaped structure with eight transparency strips and two circular card discs. There will be a central axel made from a stick whose top end will be stuck to the disc. The bottom...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Hgxivs8OYV4</id>
<title><![CDATA[TOP PATTERNS - MARATHI - 23MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:36</duration>
<date>2012-11-29</date>
<description><![CDATA[Stick a marble at the center of an old CD. The small marble jutting from the base will form a wonderful pivot. Stick some wonderful Strobe Patterns on the CD. On spinning the CD the patterns...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>CDgvm2YLgrs</id>
<title><![CDATA[MAGNETIC DOLL -  MARATHI - 9MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:24</duration>
<date>2012-11-29</date>
<description><![CDATA[Balance a straw with a needle on a cut bottle. The straw has a doll on top and a small magnet on the other. Wind 150-turns of insulated copper wire on the bottle. On connecting/disconnecting...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>EBVGPHAptr4</id>
<title><![CDATA[SOLAR FAN - MARATHI - 11MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:25</duration>
<date>2012-11-29</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is a simple exhibit to sensitize children about green energy. Fossil fuels increase the carbon in the air. Nuclear power is still unsafe. The sun is one source of clean energy. In this...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>FmJ_M0XDec8</id>
<title><![CDATA[CATAPULT PARACHUTE -  MARATHI - 18MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:05</duration>
<date>2012-11-29</date>
<description><![CDATA[The parachute is made of very thin plastic sheet, taped at eight points with a wooden stick as ballast. This parachute can be shot in the air with the help of an improvised catapult. On descent...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>q9-DWmH5qkQ</id>
<title><![CDATA[VECTOR TRICYCLE - MARATHI - 17 MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:53</duration>
<date>2012-11-29</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is an unusual Chinese tricycle. The two foot rests hinged at the hand steering. To propel the cycle forwards you need to bring your feet close and then take them apart. This action provides...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>0UfUcoqszeo</id>
<title><![CDATA[KNOTTY CRAB - MARATHI - 20MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:35</duration>
<date>2012-11-29</date>
<description><![CDATA[Take a long strip 30-cm long and 3-cm wide and tie a knot in it. Surprisingly, the middle part will be a regular pentagon. Cut the strips on both sides to make crab legs and its pincers. Draw...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>V3XEslvmWoU</id>
<title><![CDATA[SPINNER FROM SCRAP -  MARATHI - 20MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:12</duration>
<date>2012-11-29</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make two cuts at 45-degrees in plastic bottle. Cut a CD in half and inserted these pieces in the cuts of the bottle. Glue them to make two vanes. The bottle should be free to spin on a cycle...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>kPRNSGHWukE</id>
<title><![CDATA[SPINNING SPIRAL -  MARATHI - 18MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:18</duration>
<date>2012-11-29</date>
<description><![CDATA[This bottle spins beautifully. Mark and cut one spiral in a plastic bottle. Cut flaps at right angles to the spiral and lift them up like fan blades. Tape all adjacent flaps to make a continuous...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>S1JYI5OLHh8</id>
<title><![CDATA[SPINNING SPACESHIP - MARATHI -15MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:03</duration>
<date>2012-11-29</date>
<description><![CDATA[Tape two Styrofoam plates to make a biconvex spaceship. Insert four straws in the joints at right angles but pointing the same way. On blowing through the central straw air will eject out of...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>wO0-CnnU2lY</id>
<title><![CDATA[BALL BOUNCE - MARATHI - 16MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:03</duration>
<date>2012-11-29</date>
<description><![CDATA[This ball shooter is a terrific toy. Place two strong rubber bands at right angles in a cup cut from a plastic bottle. Tie a string to the cross. Place a ping-pong ball on the cross. On pulling...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>A1xzEsJtM-A</id>
<title><![CDATA[HOT AIR BAG - MARATHI - 10MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:35</duration>
<date>2012-11-29</date>
<description><![CDATA[You can make a hot air balloon in your home. Place a thin plastic bag 30-cm x 60-cm on top of an electric toaster. Soon hot air will fill the bag. The bag will become light and will take-off...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>gHdJUcDVluI</id>
<title><![CDATA[SOLAR WATER HEATER - MARATHI -18MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:22</duration>
<date>2012-11-07</date>
<description><![CDATA[This Solar Water Heater kit was designed by LG of Korea. The heart of this kit is a Fresnel lens. This flat plastic lens concentrates the rays of the sun on a bowl of water. And within an hour...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>gA1Zgj5J0nA</id>
<title><![CDATA[CHIT- CHAT CUP - MARATHI - 13MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:01</duration>
<date>2012-11-07</date>
<description><![CDATA[Draw two long rabbit ears on a paper cup and then cut them. Draw eyes and nose. Then fold the base of the cup in half to make the upper and lower jaws of the rabbit. On pressing and releasing...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>g1EFGbdCUYc</id>
<title><![CDATA[HEART FAN - MARATHI - 19MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:09</duration>
<date>2012-11-07</date>
<description><![CDATA[Cut four heart-shaped card sheets and then fold them in the midline. Stick half of each heart on a square card. The other halves will stand up and make fan blades. Mount card on a stick and...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>zZpxj2AjRR8</id>
<title><![CDATA[BIMETALLIC ALARM - MARATHI - 9MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:31</duration>
<date>2012-11-07</date>
<description><![CDATA[This wonderful kit has been designed by LG of Korea. The heart of the Fire Alarm is a bimetallic strip. When heated the strip expands completing an electric circuit. This switches ON a Fire...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>1VobcnqRb8s</id>
<title><![CDATA[BLOW BALL - MARATHI - 12MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:41</duration>
<date>2012-11-07</date>
<description><![CDATA[In this experiment an electric motor operates a high speed fan. And a fast air stream comes out of a tube. A ping-pong held on the mouth of the tube simply floats in the air stream. http://www.ar...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>jvYfsuYy2J4</id>
<title><![CDATA[FISH TAIL BOAT - MARATHI - 17MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:58</duration>
<date>2012-11-07</date>
<description><![CDATA[This fish tailed boat is a readymade kit designed by LG in Korea. An electric toy motor moves the rudder of the boat. The moving rudder pushes the water aside and propels the boat forwards....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>AOYDAxavKJ4</id>
<title><![CDATA[HELL AND HEAVEN - MARATHI - 16MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:55</duration>
<date>2012-10-22</date>
<description><![CDATA[This wonderful paper activity can be told along with a gripping story. A pious man gets a ticket to heaven. He gives one-third ticket to a greedy man and then one-third more. The greedy man's...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>5KHHoqs_L_k</id>
<title><![CDATA[SPINNING SLINKY - MARATHI - 21MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:25</duration>
<date>2012-10-17</date>
<description><![CDATA[Mount a spiral slinky on a stick. On top of the stick is a plastic fan. When the stick is placed in a stiff straw and held under a ceiling fan the circular slinky rotates and the patterns are...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Lj2-6S8lkbk</id>
<title><![CDATA[SUNLIGHT YOUR HOME - MARATHI -13MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:42</duration>
<date>2012-10-17</date>
<description><![CDATA[Hang a bottle of water in a close cardboard carton. The bottle should be half inside the box and half outside. The dark box will be lit brightly by the light coming from the bottle. This light...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Vc6-YyX-01U</id>
<title><![CDATA[TWIST THREAD SPIN -CD MARATHI - 20MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:27</duration>
<date>2012-10-17</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make two holes in an old CD with a hot needle and weave a 60-cm long thread through them. Tie beads on thread end. Spin the CD and the threads will get twisted. On gently pulling the beads...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>84wDveh5dYc</id>
<title><![CDATA[DANCE OF NINE CUBE - MARATHI -10MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>0:59</duration>
<date>2012-10-17</date>
<description><![CDATA[Collect nine similar cubical boxes and tape all the joints with cello tape. Then hold and move the model diagonally. The cubes will open up and close in a wonderful dance. Enjoy the dance of...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>S6sa5un7-KE</id>
<title><![CDATA[GEARING UP - MARATHI - 12MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:33</duration>
<date>2012-10-17</date>
<description><![CDATA[In this toy a small gear rotates with the help of a fan. As this small gear spins it spins a larger gear. On the large gear are mounted two figures and they merrily dance. This delightful dynamic...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>tmFBXU68BJs</id>
<title><![CDATA[TREE NAME PLATE - MARATHI -26MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:37</duration>
<date>2012-10-16</date>
<description><![CDATA[Teachers can inculcate an interest in children regarding trees by involving them in making tree name plates. Tree names can be punched on Aluminum plates or written on Tetrapaks with ball pens....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>fLWBQ8KcRSg</id>
<title><![CDATA[PULL AND FLAP - MARATHI - 24MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:32</duration>
<date>2012-10-16</date>
<description><![CDATA[Stick the central body of butterfly made from a transparency on a thick board. Attach two threads to the butterfly wings. Pass both threads through a bead stuck to the central body of the butterfly...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>wlA3TvmX9n8</id>
<title><![CDATA[CAN TILT - MARATHI - 10MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:16</duration>
<date>2012-10-16</date>
<description><![CDATA[Take an empty coke aluminum can. Cut it in half. You can keep this half can tilted by placing a heavy ball bearing inside it. Then the aluminum half-can will stand tilted at an angle of 45-degrees....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>u_ge-bbz_6s</id>
<title><![CDATA[LOUD LID - MARATHI - 13MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:35</duration>
<date>2012-10-16</date>
<description><![CDATA[Press fit a long plastic pen tube in a bottle lid. Press a hard straw on the rim for blowing. Stretch a torn balloon on the lid to make a taut membrane. Push the pen from below to touch the...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>1CAILIIAeSk</id>
<title><![CDATA[LEAF CREATURE - MARATHI - 11MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:32</duration>
<date>2012-10-16</date>
<description><![CDATA[This amazing leaf creature is made from a leaf and a stiff twig. Cut two slants on a leaf and then bend them into a cone. The top portion of the leaf is then folded as the face of the animal....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>vkIgegqGVak</id>
<title><![CDATA[HAND UP - MARATHI - 11MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:23</duration>
<date>2012-10-16</date>
<description><![CDATA[Cut and remove the base of a plastic 1-liter bottle. Place and secure a medical rubber glove on the bottle mouth. Now as you push this bottle in a jar of water air will be expelled from the...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>B41SGPjXuEs</id>
<title><![CDATA[SAND STRENGTH - MARATHI - 13MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:51</duration>
<date>2012-08-06</date>
<description><![CDATA[The end of the tube is tied with a toilet paper. Sand is gently filled and packed in the tube. On top is attached a seat where a child can sit. Because the sand is packed very tightly it is...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>iF9AxEsCghg</id>
<title><![CDATA[WINDING MOTION - MARATHI - 11MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:34</duration>
<date>2012-08-06</date>
<description><![CDATA[This toy is a refined version of an old toy made from a wooden bobbin and rubber band. As you wind the rubber band twists and stores energy. On keeping the toy on the floor it will shoot forwards...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>oDyGblZM4xw</id>
<title><![CDATA[MAGNETIC ROTATION - MARATHI - 13MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:42</duration>
<date>2012-08-06</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is a very simple magnetic toy. A propeller is cut from an old bottle and its petals twisted to make fan blades. The shaft of the fan has two ring magnets. When placed in contact with other...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>15F3D26AMyM</id>
<title><![CDATA[MAGIC WATER FLOW - MARATHI - 14MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:49</duration>
<date>2012-08-06</date>
<description><![CDATA[This magic water fountain is assembled from a readymade kit. Water flows from a tap which seems to hang in thin air. But actually the tap is securely mounted on a transparent inlet tube. The...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>H1PNu8YGI4M</id>
<title><![CDATA[CRANKY WOODCUTTER - MARATHI - 7MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>0:58</duration>
<date>2012-08-06</date>
<description><![CDATA[The heart of this woodcutter is a crank made of wire. So as you rotate the crank the man hits the log with an axe as if he was chopping wood. This beautiful and dynamic model is made from simple...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>tAsNQB_nRt0</id>
<title><![CDATA[FLOAT AND SPIN - MARATHI - 15MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:58</duration>
<date>2012-07-20</date>
<description><![CDATA[A bottle has two straws outlets bent in opposite directions and stands on a Styrofoam plate. Close the straw ends and fill the bottle with water. On opening the straw ends water will flow out...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>odsfXt0y3kw</id>
<title><![CDATA[FARMER'S STORY - MARATHI - 11MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:51</duration>
<date>2012-07-18</date>
<description><![CDATA[This amazing tale of a farmer can be told with the help of a string. First the farmer ploughs the field, then sows seeds, then waters and manures. But when the harvest is ready a fat rat comes...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>dXZapGL-ivk</id>
<title><![CDATA[JUMPING FROG - MARATHI - 26MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>3:04</duration>
<date>2012-07-13</date>
<description><![CDATA[Fold a jumping frog from a 20-cm x 10-cm sheet of rectangular paper. This frog looks like a real frog and mimics it too. On pressing its paper spring the frog leaps forwards. The challenge...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>bBpc2UycYfw</id>
<title><![CDATA[HOW MANY THINGS IN A MATCHBOX ? - MARATHI - 15MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:01</duration>
<date>2012-07-12</date>
<description><![CDATA[How many little things -- one of each, can be packed in a matchbox? Children will search and find many micro things around them. Thirty years back children managed to pack 250 small specimens...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>XAULxd_NCXo</id>
<title><![CDATA[STICK MULTIPLICATION - MARATHI - 29MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>4:18</duration>
<date>2012-07-10</date>
<description><![CDATA[When two broomsticks are kept across they meet at one junction (1 x 1 = 1). Similarly 3 vertical and 2 horizontal sticks will have 3 x 2 = 6 junctions. Using 18 sticks children can recreate...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>1XNkypfyywY</id>
<title><![CDATA[CALENDER FUN  - MARATHI - 42MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>5:32</duration>
<date>2012-07-06</date>
<description><![CDATA[This video is based on a book NUMBER FUN WITH A CALENDAR written by P. K. Srinivasan. There are amazing number patterns hidden in a calendar. You will see many arithmetic series hidden in ...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>mByflBFZOHo</id>
<title><![CDATA[WIRE PROPELLOR -  MARATHI - 9MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:13</duration>
<date>2012-05-04</date>
<description><![CDATA[This wire propeller is a spinning toy. Its fan is made of stiff plastic. Petals are cut and twisted to make the fan. When placed under the ceiling fan the toy spin very smoothly. http://www.arvind...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>GHbDbdEylBI</id>
<title><![CDATA[SPINNING DIVER -  MARATHI - 12MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:48</duration>
<date>2012-05-04</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is a variation of the Cartesian Diver. Here the diver is made from a dropper. An aluminum fan is attached to the dropper. On squeezing the bottle because of the aluminum fan the dropper...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Ia_r62sQeKc</id>
<title><![CDATA[MAGNETIC MOVEMENT -  MARATHI - 11MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:00</duration>
<date>2012-05-04</date>
<description><![CDATA[This experiment is an adaption of an old toy. A vertical bottle propeller is mounted on top of a cycle spoke. A ring magnet is placed in the spoke. This makes its tip magnetic. When placed...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>2flk9S8qiEs</id>
<title><![CDATA[LIGHT EXPERIMENTS -  MARATHI - 18MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:50</duration>
<date>2012-05-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[Do a series of light experiments using a fish tank, laser torch and various mirrors and lenses. In these experiments you can actually see the path of light -- the way rays reflect, converge...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>fdcPytcup-I</id>
<title><![CDATA[BALLOON DIVER - MARATHI - 12 MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:58</duration>
<date>2012-04-26</date>
<description><![CDATA[The balloon diver is an old toy. Attach a paper clip to a balloon or a shampoo pouch to make it slightly heavy. Place it in a bottle full of water. Shut the lid tight. On pressing the bottle...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>hpThoFjE0tY</id>
<title><![CDATA[TURBINE SPRINKLER- MARATHI - 23MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:55</duration>
<date>2012-04-26</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is essentially a straw sprinkler with a turbine mounted on the top of its shaft. As you blow on the turbine with a straw the turbine spins and so does the sprinkler. The sprinkler throws...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>98V8Vy8rCts</id>
<title><![CDATA[TURBINE SPINNER- MARATHI - 19 MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:34</duration>
<date>2012-04-26</date>
<description><![CDATA[This turbine looks like a gear and is made of card sheet. It is mounted on a wire axle. As you blow though a straw air strikes the blades of the turbine and it spins very fast. http://www.arvindgu...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>bz8vDPDmfnc</id>
<title><![CDATA[MAGNETIC GLASS SPINNER - MARATHI - 18MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:03</duration>
<date>2012-04-26</date>
<description><![CDATA[Cut one-fourth of a paper cup and make a 1-cm diameter hole in its base. Place a ring magnet on top and below this hole. The magnets will stick to each other. Place the magnets on a cycle spoke...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>VYyPSHTcwig</id>
<title><![CDATA[SOAP PEARL - MARATHI - 9MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:18</duration>
<date>2012-01-16</date>
<description><![CDATA[Fill a syringe with diluted liquid soap solution. Press the syringe so that drops fall on the soap solution. You will find that the drops instead of mixing with the liquid they actually float...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>d4p74TZ7Krs</id>
<title><![CDATA[PEARL ON TARO LEAF - MARATHI - 8MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:17</duration>
<date>2012-01-16</date>
<description><![CDATA[Take a Corm leaf or a lotus leaf. Place water on it with a dropper. The water drop will float and will not stick to the leaf. This is because these leaves have a spiky coating on top. This...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>rbFdfUEpzHs</id>
<title><![CDATA[PEARL ON HOTPAN - MARATHI - 12MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:59</duration>
<date>2011-12-29</date>
<description><![CDATA[Heat a spoon on a flame. Place a drop of water on the spoon when it becomes really hot. The water drop will float on the spoon like a beautiful and transparent pearl. This is called the Lyndon...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>hQwhscjT9Mk</id>
<title><![CDATA[ANNEALING IN ACTION - MARATHI - 7MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:15</duration>
<date>2011-12-29</date>
<description><![CDATA[Do metallurgy in your kitchen. Straighten two paper clips. Heat one wire for two minutes in a flame and plunge it in cold heat. Heat the other and let it cool slowly. The first wire will become...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>2gPa6QgVTUI</id>
<title><![CDATA[WINE TEARS -  MARATHI - 7MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:29</duration>
<date>2011-12-21</date>
<description><![CDATA[Fill one-third of the cup with port wine. Shake it a few times and then leave it. The alcohol in the wine will evaporate but water will remain. Slowly, droplets of water will form and roll...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>rJfuTsjwc9o</id>
<title><![CDATA[CAPILLARY ACTION -  MARATHI - 7MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:13</duration>
<date>2011-12-21</date>
<description><![CDATA[Place two slides one of top of the other. Place a rubber band on one end and wedge a paper clip on the other. Place the slides in color water. Because of Capillary Action water will immediately...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>4U4sKCjZLEo</id>
<title><![CDATA[ADD SUGAR, BEND LIGHT -  MARATHI - 8MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:21</duration>
<date>2011-12-16</date>
<description><![CDATA[Fill a fish tank with 3-litres of water. Add 250-gm sugar. Don't stir it. The sugar will automatically dissolve. A laser beam will go straight at the top but will bend at the lower level because...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>8jz06OJzqas</id>
<title><![CDATA[SOLID LIQUID -  MARATHI - 13MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:59</duration>
<date>2011-12-16</date>
<description><![CDATA[Mix two parts corn flour and one part water in a bowl to make flowing slurry. You will be able to dip your fingers slowly in the slurry. But on hitting the slurry with your fist you will encounter...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>DB_r-18ZZCc</id>
<title><![CDATA[SEE STRESS -  MARATHI - 10MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:49</duration>
<date>2011-12-16</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is a fun experiment. See stresses in materials with the help of polarized lenses and neon light. On placing a plastic ruler under this apparatus you will see colored lines representing...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>FwvFJnJZ5aU</id>
<title><![CDATA[SAND SUCKS -  MARATHI - 15MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:44</duration>
<date>2011-12-16</date>
<description><![CDATA[Fill a plastic bottle with three-quarters coarse sand. Add water to saturate the sand with water. Let a little water float on top. On squeezing the bottle more water should pour out. Instead,...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>ucrj9YxCE1A</id>
<title><![CDATA[FLOWING CHARGE - MARATHI - 12MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:54</duration>
<date>2011-12-15</date>
<description><![CDATA[Water flows through a transparent tube filled with glass granules carries with surface electrons from the granules. This creates a potential difference between the two ends of the tube. This...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>uc6ILEOGpeU</id>
<title><![CDATA[SUN IS ONE - MARATHI - 6MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:00</duration>
<date>2011-11-18</date>
<description><![CDATA[A card sheet has cut out symbols of different religions -- Christianity, Hinduism and Islam. You will see the shadows of these symbols -- the cross, moon etc on the ground. On raising the card...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>5Uz0WLaY7dU</id>
<title><![CDATA[RESONANT PETALS - MARATHI - 12MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:20</duration>
<date>2011-11-18</date>
<description><![CDATA[See resonance of petals with this readymade head massager. There are big and small prongs to scratch your head. Pluck a big prong and another big prong will vibrate. Each time you pluck a prong...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>rN2iXJJXsns</id>
<title><![CDATA[FLOPPY PROPELLER - MARATHI - 17MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:12</duration>
<date>2011-11-18</date>
<description><![CDATA[Old floppy discs have no use and are just thrown away. Cut eight petals in the floppy disc. Then twist them into blades. Mount this fan on a pencil with a magnet. The surrounding three magnets...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>j9Pdwi327Rc</id>
<title><![CDATA[BERNOULLI BAG - MARATHI - 12MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:10</duration>
<date>2011-11-18</date>
<description><![CDATA[Tie a knot at one end of a 2-meter long flexible plastic tube used for making plastic bags. This will seal that end. Then blow a lungful of air with your mouth next to the tube. This will be...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>oWvR6wM_mjU</id>
<title><![CDATA[SPIRAL ILLUSION -  MARATHI - 20MB]]></title>
<duration>2:07</duration>
<date>2011-09-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[Glue a marble in the center of an old CD / DVD. The CD will spin like a top on the marble pivot. Stick a Spiral Illusion pattern on the CD. This spinning pattern will appear as if the spiral...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>SlBJ7IEcz3w</id>
<title><![CDATA[SYNTHETIC BOUNCY BALL -  MARATHI - 14MB]]></title>
<duration>1:38</duration>
<date>2011-09-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[Mix borax and synthetic glue with a little bit of water in a bowl. The borax will make a cross-linked polymer and the mixture will soon turn into a semi-solid jelly. You can easily shape this...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>eVLCQdgCkdw</id>
<title><![CDATA[POKE A BALLOON - MARATHI - 18MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:46</duration>
<date>2011-09-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[If you poke a needle in a balloon near its mouth (South Pole) or its apex (North Pole) it will not burst because the skin is not stretched fully. However, when the balloon is poked on its equator...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>i69P3gnwBr8</id>
<title><![CDATA[PAPER SKELETON - MARATHI - 35MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>3:50</duration>
<date>2011-09-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[With half an A-4 size paper you can make a scale model of the human skeleton. Cut the paper in 8 equal parts. Make the skull, ribcage, pelvis, hands, legs and other bones out of them. All bones...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>PkVTugKIyng</id>
<title><![CDATA[TRADITIONAL IRRIGATION LADLE - MARATHI - 7MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>0:59</duration>
<date>2011-09-14</date>
<description><![CDATA[With two pairs of thread and a paper cup you can make this old irrigation ladle. Fill the cup with buttons. The cup is hung by threads to a cycle spoke. On pulling the end pairs apart the ladle...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>hyWo7Lg6xDg</id>
<title><![CDATA[CD-COIN SPINNER - MARATHI - 10MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:23</duration>
<date>2011-09-12</date>
<description><![CDATA[A coin is heated and then embedded vertically in the center of an old CD. The coin will be fixed without glue. You can hold the coin and spin it freely on a smooth table. Glue a Newton's disc...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>FxWl37zIV6I</id>
<title><![CDATA[BUTTERFLY IN A BOTTLE - MARATHI - 9MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:08</duration>
<date>2011-09-12</date>
<description><![CDATA[Remove the end cap of a fused glass bulb. Cut a plastic bottle near its neck. Stick this bottle piece to the glass bulb. Mount a butterfly in the lid and then screw it on. This is very good...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>dCgONfUY6D0</id>
<title><![CDATA[MATCHSTICK TURBINE - MARATHI - 8MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:07</duration>
<date>2011-09-12</date>
<description><![CDATA[This turbine is made by sticking matchstick along the radii of a thick circular card. The central pivot is a thumb tack. Place the turbine on the table and blow on the disc to make it spin....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Kem1kjLAhR8</id>
<title><![CDATA[PEN DANCE - MARATHI - 10MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:22</duration>
<date>2011-09-12</date>
<description><![CDATA[Tie two dried sketch pens with a rubber band. Rotate the pens so there are many twists in the rubber band. On placing the pens on a table they will dance and jump very animatedly as if they...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>_rU4HRj_pKM</id>
<title><![CDATA[INSET PUZZLE - MARATHI - 13MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:38</duration>
<date>2011-09-12</date>
<description><![CDATA[You can easily carve a Styrofoam block so that it goes through windows of three different shapes -- a circle, a square and a triangle. This is an old but challenging puzzle. The Styrofoam block...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>JRU7-ZrCdrA</id>
<title><![CDATA[PLUCK STRING SPIN RING - MARATHI - 6MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>0:59</duration>
<date>2011-09-12</date>
<description><![CDATA[Weave circular colored card disks with a hole in the center in a string. Keep the string taut. On plucking the string the disks will start spinning because of the vibrations. Spin a Newton's...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>NiOAhZV50Xw</id>
<title><![CDATA[STRAW SPRAY - MARATHI - 10MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>0:58</duration>
<date>2011-09-12</date>
<description><![CDATA[Cut and bend a straw at right angles. Place one end in water and blow from the other end. A misty spray will come from the other end. Similarly, using a fat straw you can blow out small Styrofoam...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>ZPhq0-Ys0uU</id>
<title><![CDATA[BRUSH IN RUSH - MARATHI -10MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:30</duration>
<date>2011-09-12</date>
<description><![CDATA[Salvage the vibrator motor of an old Mobile phone and mount it on an old toothbrush. Place it on a table and connect motor to battery. The brush will vibrate and dance in a very interesting...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>pLghJ5_nJqE</id>
<title><![CDATA[WIRE FLOWERS - MARATHI - 10MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:19</duration>
<date>2011-09-12</date>
<description><![CDATA[MAKE FLOWERS FROM SPRING LIKE BINDING WIRE !]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>hmysQnIr_P4</id>
<title><![CDATA[DUMP TRUCK - MARATHI - 18MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>2:27</duration>
<date>2011-09-12</date>
<description><![CDATA[This delightful dump-truck moves on button wheels. When you press a lever the loading platform lifts up at an angle and unloads the cargo. This amazing dump truck can be made with two matchboxes,.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>zuQ0ImIArnI</id>
<title><![CDATA[MOTOR BUG - MARATHI - 10MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:18</duration>
<date>2011-09-08</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make a bug with four wire legs and place a Mobile phone vibrator motor on it. On attaching it to a 1.5-volt battery the bug will start vibrating and execute a very intriguing bug dance. Many...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>MJAVdyIeaJY</id>
<title><![CDATA[AEOLIAN TOP - MARATHI - 10MB.avi]]></title>
<duration>1:06</duration>
<date>2011-09-08</date>
<description><![CDATA[The Aeolian Top or the Air Top is a fantastic toy. It is made of thick card with flaps. When air strikes the flaps the top spins on a thumb tack pivot. On direction air through a straw than...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>7GLvcuJ5JLg</id>
<title><![CDATA[FISHY FISH - MARATHI - 26MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:56</duration>
<date>2011-05-18</date>
<description><![CDATA[This wonderful model depicts waves of the sea made from cut strips. The strips are phased out to give a 3-dimensional effect. Inside these waves you can hide different sea creatures -- especially...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>STi2i644S5U</id>
<title><![CDATA[SIMPLE ROCKET - MARATHI - 29 MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>2:10</duration>
<date>2011-05-17</date>
<description><![CDATA[A DELIGHTFUL FUN ROCKET FROM A BALLOON !]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>adISHi9AYug</id>
<title><![CDATA[TOTAL INTERNAL REFLECTION - MARATHI - 20MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:33</duration>
<date>2011-05-17</date>
<description><![CDATA[Place water in a glass bottle with a few drops of Dettol. By pointing a laser beam at an angle you can show Total Internal Reflection. In this case the incident ray will strike the water surface,...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>V45tpBMPI7w</id>
<title><![CDATA[MUSICAL GLASS - MARATHI - 19 MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:22</duration>
<date>2011-05-17</date>
<description><![CDATA[MAKE MUSIC WITH WINE GLASSES !]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>YGa9Yn7i2sA</id>
<title><![CDATA[COOL COLOURS - MARATHI - 31 MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>2:25</duration>
<date>2011-05-17</date>
<description><![CDATA[SEE THE DANCE OF COLOR SHADOWS WITH THESE L.E.D.s.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>-qHidgbCRv8</id>
<title><![CDATA[BLACK BOTTLE SOLAR HEATER - MARATHI - 17MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:25</duration>
<date>2011-05-17</date>
<description><![CDATA[Take two 1-litre plastic bottles one covered with black and other with white paper. Fill both bottles with equal amounts of tap water. Initial temperature of water was 29-degree Celsius. After...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>QnZwM7Dn6nY</id>
<title><![CDATA[SOLAR TOY CAR - MARATHI - 15MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:05</duration>
<date>2011-05-17</date>
<description><![CDATA[This Solar Car is a readymade Chinese Toy. The important wheel is in the middle. This wheel both powers the car and also turns it. The solar panel generates current and runs the car. When the...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Slxyg5idqN4</id>
<title><![CDATA[WALKING CYLINDER - MARATHI - 30MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>2:07</duration>
<date>2011-05-17</date>
<description><![CDATA[This Walking Cylinder is made from a toilet roll, straws and other odd materials. If you place the cylinder on a gentle incline it will roll with its legs moving -- as if the cylinder was walking....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>8GDcAy7OHHQ</id>
<title><![CDATA[SIMPLE ANIMATION ON FLY-WHEEL - MARATHI - 11MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>0:53</duration>
<date>2011-05-17</date>
<description><![CDATA[In this simple mechanism a spoke rotates on pulling a thread. A card sheet with a Bird on one side and a Cage on the other side rotate with the spoke. As you pull the thread the spoke rotates...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>qurxuc9t3S4</id>
<title><![CDATA[SOLAR HEATER - MARATHI - 12MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:02</duration>
<date>2011-05-17</date>
<description><![CDATA[In winters we wear dark clothes because they absorb a lot more heat. Take two aluminum cans -- one black and the other shiny. Fill both cans to the top with water. Then keep both cans out in...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>fjUKMarN4cw</id>
<title><![CDATA[FIBER OPTICS - MARATHI - 20MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:29</duration>
<date>2011-05-17</date>
<description><![CDATA[Fill a bottomless plastic bottle with Dettol water. Make a hole in its lid. Shine the toy laser in the middle of the hole. As water exits from the hole, light will bend along with it. This...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>u94D2_LzFVk</id>
<title><![CDATA[CASANOVA CASE - MARATHI - 37MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>2:49</duration>
<date>2011-05-17</date>
<description><![CDATA[Using a card sheet you can make a very elegant case. You will need a card sheet, needle, divider, scissors, glue etc. First make this pattern on the card then cut and glue it. The finished...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Zrklw7CYi5o</id>
<title><![CDATA[TENSEGRITY STRUCUTRES - MARATHI - 26MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:58</duration>
<date>2011-05-17</date>
<description><![CDATA[You will need 3 stiff straws and 4 loops of wool to make this tensegrity structure. Hold the straws at right angles -- like the three x y and z axes. Insert the first loop in the straws and...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>1ZhhTo72wSM</id>
<title><![CDATA[CUP HELICOPTER - MARATHI - 21MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:34</duration>
<date>2011-04-19</date>
<description><![CDATA[Remove the base of a paper cup and cut four petals from the hoop. Remove the rim from the base of the second cup. Stick the four petals on the base of the second cup. Give the petals a twist...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>GMzJDCBnD6k</id>
<title><![CDATA[TWIN TOPS - MARATHI - 15MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:11</duration>
<date>2011-04-19</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make a small hole in the center of a film can lid. Fix a toothpick tightly in it as an axle. Twirl this top and it will spin well. Similarly make a top from a table support pad. Give it a twirl...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>3paCZerND_Y</id>
<title><![CDATA[HOMOPOLAR MOTOR - MARATHI - 11 MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:00</duration>
<date>2011-04-19</date>
<description><![CDATA[A SIMPLE ELECTRIC MOTOR !]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>hH7oDgf1lcA</id>
<title><![CDATA[JEANS BAGS - MARATHI - 20MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:28</duration>
<date>2011-04-19</date>
<description><![CDATA[The jeans bag is a classic example of doing more with less. Old jeans often get frayed at the knees and can be cut and sewn to make a very cool bag. You can pack lots of boxes and bags and...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>twpGQYXtztc</id>
<title><![CDATA[WHITE SWAN - MARATHI - 36MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>2:34</duration>
<date>2011-04-19</date>
<description><![CDATA[You need hundreds of small squares to make this white swan. Cut a rectangle in half and make two squares. One square is needed to fold a modular unit to make the swan. You will need 500 such...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>SNFa43GMn24</id>
<title><![CDATA[DANCING EYES - MARATHI - 17MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:21</duration>
<date>2011-04-19</date>
<description><![CDATA[This is a very simple animation. Take a doubled strip of paper. Draw two similar faces -- one exactly on top of the other. Make eyeballs to the left on the top one and to the right on the bottom...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>NiG3V7KXVxw</id>
<title><![CDATA[SIMPLE CONDUCTION - MARATHI - 20MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:40</duration>
<date>2011-04-19</date>
<description><![CDATA[Stick a series of small nails with wax on a hacksaw blade. Now heat one end of the hacksaw blade. As the blade heats up the wax will melt and the nails will drop in a sequence. This is a very...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>xXD3Zf6vGa8</id>
<title><![CDATA[FIDO-DIDO CLOWN - MARATHI - 19MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:23</duration>
<date>2011-04-18</date>
<description><![CDATA[Take a rectangular box made of card sheet. Cut four flaps. Attach all the body parts of Fido-Dido to the flaps - the face, the two hands and finally the legs. The clown is now ready to do a...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>O1GnkC1AA4k</id>
<title><![CDATA[CLIMBING MAN - MARATHI - 22MB]]></title>
<duration>1:38</duration>
<date>2011-04-18</date>
<description><![CDATA[The toy is essentially made from a paper strip. The two separate channel strips are joined by a triangle above. Cut a small triangle from top and paint a happy face. Place this face between...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>XS6wU-GZBjo</id>
<title><![CDATA[FLAT FLEXAGON - MARATHI - 42MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>3:20</duration>
<date>2011-04-18</date>
<description><![CDATA[Fold a big square into 16 little squares. Crease well and remove the middle four squares. There will only be 12 small squares left. Now write 1 in four squares as shown. Write 2 in four other...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>beNF_Tr531w</id>
<title><![CDATA[STRAW STATIC - MARATHI - 15MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:12</duration>
<date>2011-04-18</date>
<description><![CDATA[Push a paper pin in the middle of a straw. Place the pin in a refill for smooth rotation. Rub both ends of the white straw with wool to electrically charge it. On bringing another yellow charged...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>XsvzTi60Ois</id>
<title><![CDATA[PAPER APERTURE - MARATHI - 39MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>2:46</duration>
<date>2011-04-18</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make this paper aperture with eight same size squares of different colors. This is modular origami. Make 8 similar modules and then assemble them. It will be an octagon with a hole in the middle....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Q6mjC10KkXE</id>
<title><![CDATA[SPOOL GENERATOR - MARATHI - 32MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>2:18</duration>
<date>2011-04-18</date>
<description><![CDATA[229. SPOOL GENERATOR Take a plumber's Teflon Tape spool and wind 800 turns of insulated copper wire on it. Attach ends to a LED. Mount two neodymium magnets on the cover so that they can ...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>LubXMJs-k7c</id>
<title><![CDATA[TRAFFIC POLICE - MARATHI - 28MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>2:04</duration>
<date>2011-04-18</date>
<description><![CDATA[Cut four 'V' notches in a thin straw. Weave thread through it and tape thread at one end. Pull the thread and the straw will curl and bend. On releasing the straw will straighten. Now make...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>4NbYMVLiCnw</id>
<title><![CDATA[TORNADO WELL - MARATHI - 26MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:53</duration>
<date>2011-04-01</date>
<description><![CDATA[Glue a plastic CD strip on a cycle spoke to make a spinner. Mount a fan improvised from a bottle on the spoke. Place the spinner in the box filled half with water. Place this assembly under...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>8TLAZxWdSOw</id>
<title><![CDATA[TRIANGLE GRID - MARATHI - 36MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>2:42</duration>
<date>2011-04-01</date>
<description><![CDATA[Cut out the biggest square from an A-4 size paper. Fold the mid-line. Then fold through one corner while placing the other corner on the mid-line. This way you will fold 60-degree angles. Continue...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>UJL6cBA1L2c</id>
<title><![CDATA[SQUARE TO CYLINDER - MARATHI - 27MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:56</duration>
<date>2011-04-01</date>
<description><![CDATA[It is unbelievable but you can fold a 2-D paper square into a 3-D cylinder. First fold a 'Z' shaped spring. Then fold the square into 8 equal parts and crease there diagonals. Holding the top...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>D-6xFxO__Ec</id>
<title><![CDATA[INSIDE OUTSIDE CUBE - MARATHI - 30MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>2:12</duration>
<date>2011-04-01</date>
<description><![CDATA[This toy is made from a strip of old tetrapak by marking four squares and four triangles. The creases are scored and the flap glued to complete the cube. First fold the model to make a Silver...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Nn_9CLF1ZNo</id>
<title><![CDATA[BOTTLE TURBINE - MARATHI - 20MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:35</duration>
<date>2011-04-01</date>
<description><![CDATA[This amazing toy was designed by Durga a school girl coming from a very poor family. She won a big prize for this innovation. A small card sheet turbine is mounted on a bottle lid with a hole....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>0r90BACP0kk</id>
<title><![CDATA[SHIMMERING MATCHBOX - MARATHI - 14MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:07</duration>
<date>2011-04-01</date>
<description><![CDATA[Fix two paper clips on the edges of a matchbox shell. Weave the thread through the clips and tie beads on both ends. To make it work well you may have to push-pull and adjust drawer. Hold the...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>oG4Kd_3dyO0</id>
<title><![CDATA[BOX SPRINKLER - MARATHI - 21MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:30</duration>
<date>2011-04-01</date>
<description><![CDATA[In this experiment a straw sprinkler is mounted inside an old CD box. On top of the straw sprinkler is a fan improvised from a plastic bottle. The lower end of the sprinkler dips in water....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>_WoPkLhkuzA</id>
<title><![CDATA[SWEET FIRE - MARATHI - 9 MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>0:45</duration>
<date>2011-04-01</date>
<description><![CDATA[SQUEEZE AN ORANGE PEEL TO MAKE BRIGHT LIGHT!!]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>T6RMFH0Txdk</id>
<title><![CDATA[FUNNY MONEY - MARATHI - 17MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:14</duration>
<date>2011-02-10</date>
<description><![CDATA[This experiment is very graphic demonstration of Centrifugal Force. Pull an aluminum hanger and bend it into a diamond shape. Then upturn it and gently perch a heavy coin on the hook. Hang...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>wsycgWENaAk</id>
<title><![CDATA[SATELLITE SPINNER - MARATHI - 11MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>0:51</duration>
<date>2011-02-10</date>
<description><![CDATA[The Satellite Spinner is made with a plastic pen. The two silver foil arms at the rear end look like solar-panels of a satellite. Lift the clip of the pen lid at an acute angle and perch it...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>nWE8e0OBDjM</id>
<title><![CDATA[JET CAR - MARATHI - 13MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:01</duration>
<date>2011-02-10</date>
<description><![CDATA[This jet car is essentially a plastic bottle with wheels. It has a bent straw with one end on top and the other end on the tail end. When an inflated balloon is tied on the top of the straw,...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>zERJnfUQR3Y</id>
<title><![CDATA[BOTTLE LID SPINNER - MARATHI - 11 MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>0:51</duration>
<date>2011-02-10</date>
<description><![CDATA[MAKE THIS AMAZING SPINNER FROM A BOTTLE LID !]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>FsuSVz0XFus</id>
<title><![CDATA[SYRINGE AIR FAN - MARATHI - 22MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:43</duration>
<date>2011-02-10</date>
<description><![CDATA[The fan is made by cutting 12-petal from a plastic bottle. They are then twisted and turned into fan blade. This fan is mounted on a cycle spoke. The fan and spoke assembly is placed inside...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>bhNL_wVsExM</id>
<title><![CDATA[MOVING MONKEYS - MARATHI - 20MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:27</duration>
<date>2011-02-10</date>
<description><![CDATA[A stiff straw piece is vertically tied to one end of an ice-cream stick. On the other hand are two thick card monkeys. A cut rubber band is woven through the straw and kept in tension. On releasing...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>UPm3w5XcNyE</id>
<title><![CDATA[SPINNING SPINDLE - MARATHI - 24MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:46</duration>
<date>2011-02-10</date>
<description><![CDATA[You can carry this small, low-cost toy in your pocket. It is made with half an ice-cream stick with 'V' notches on both ends and two loops of thread. The stick is wedged between the threads...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>HIqgUu8E6DI</id>
<title><![CDATA[MAGNETIC AIR FAN - MARATHI - 25MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>2:04</duration>
<date>2011-02-10</date>
<description><![CDATA[You will need two strong ring-roller magnets. Insert two roller magnets in the spoke to a bottle fan and place them on the steel container. On placing the toy under a ceiling fan the bottle...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>C6YNFiL1npY</id>
<title><![CDATA[SHIMMERING FISH - MARATHI - 21MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:37</duration>
<date>2011-02-10</date>
<description><![CDATA[A pen cap is mounted off-center in a vertical thread held in tension. A screw is attached to the pen cap to make it heavy. On releasing the pen falls in short jerks. Now stick a paper fish...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>WNc9rACiBJg</id>
<title><![CDATA[MOTHER TERESA'S MEDICINE POUCH - MARATHI - 23 MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:40</duration>
<date>2010-10-11</date>
<description><![CDATA[MEDICINE PAPER BAG FOR THE POOR !]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Mf5Q5R9hBic</id>
<title><![CDATA[GOING GEARS - MARATHI - 12MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>0:58</duration>
<date>2010-10-11</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make a small and a big gear by sticking corrugated paper on a small and big lid. The gears must mesh. The small gear has a propeller on top. When placed under a ceiling fan it rotates. The...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>xbDhaSIvTGs</id>
<title><![CDATA[EGG IN BOTTLE -  MARATHI - 20MB]]></title>
<duration>1:30</duration>
<date>2010-10-11</date>
<description><![CDATA[Cut the bottle from the top and fill it half with water. Add enough salt so that a fresh egg just floats in water. Now the egg will have the same density as that of salt water. Now tape the...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>egjKaotubks</id>
<title><![CDATA[CUT POTATO TURNS BROWN - MARATHI - 12MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>0:57</duration>
<date>2010-10-04</date>
<description><![CDATA[Cut the raw potato in two-halves. Cover one-half potato with lemon juice. Leave the other half exposed to the air. After a while the piece covered with lemon juice will remain white while the...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>zUWv9ia1Ryc</id>
<title><![CDATA[POTATO INERTIA - MARATHI - 9MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>0:46</duration>
<date>2010-10-04</date>
<description><![CDATA[Can you lift a potato with a straw without touching the potato with your hands? Close the tip of the straw with your finger and strike the potato hard with it. The straw will pierce the potato...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>-xzMn_kXtGU</id>
<title><![CDATA[LIFT RICE - MARATHI - 20MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:29</duration>
<date>2010-10-04</date>
<description><![CDATA[You can lift rice in a very ingenious way. Fill a glass bottle to the top with rice. Push the blade of a long screwdriver in the rice. Remove the screwdriver and repeat this action a few more...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>OFyQVeP6UE0</id>
<title><![CDATA[ROCKET PROJECTILE - MARATHI - 25MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:55</duration>
<date>2010-10-04</date>
<description><![CDATA[This Rocket Projectile is made from a 30-cm long PVC pipe and cones folded from paper. The circular end of the cone just fits into the PVC pipe. Place a cone and adjust the pipe at 45-degrees...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>GYqrqZ3MK-Q</id>
<title><![CDATA[COLOURFUL STAR - MARATHI - 25 MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:53</duration>
<date>2010-10-04</date>
<description><![CDATA[MAKE A BEAUTIFUL ORIGAMI STAR !]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>vhnMjYp9JPE</id>
<title><![CDATA[GREEN SNAKE - MARATHI - 23MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:47</duration>
<date>2010-09-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make a Green Snake using strands of the coconut leaf. Fold two coconut strands - one on the other in a sequence. The strands will interlock and not open up. Add a tail and a head to complete...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>U8XHaTpccpE</id>
<title><![CDATA[FLEXAGON - MARATHI - 37 MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>2:53</duration>
<date>2010-09-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[Designed by a Harvard mathematician this is the most amazing rotating paper model. On rotating each time a different facet of the model will be exposed. This dynamic paper model can be graphically...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>4R2a7D_jcH4</id>
<title><![CDATA[MAGNETIC SLOW SLIDE -  MARATHI  - 8 MB]]></title>
<duration>0:42</duration>
<date>2010-09-03</date>
<description><![CDATA[A strong magnet moving on an inclined Aluminum plate slows down because of 'eddy currents'. On the other hand a steel washer of the same size and shape moves much faster on an Aluminum plate.]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Rsabz7VAaQc</id>
<title><![CDATA[THREE BLADE FAN - MARATHI - 21MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:34</duration>
<date>2010-08-23</date>
<description><![CDATA[The Three-blade Fan is an old traditional toy. Three equal strips of paper are folded in the middle to make 'V' shapes. These strips are then interlocked so as to make a cone in the centre....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>VvmxOw6cSgs</id>
<title><![CDATA[NO MAGNET MOTOR - MARATHI - 32MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>2:55</duration>
<date>2010-08-23</date>
<description><![CDATA[Instead of a permanent magnet this motor has an electromagnet which is made by winding insulated copper wire on a sewing machine bobbin. Its spinning coil is made out a meter long insulated...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>BepaaL6Mff8</id>
<title><![CDATA[TWIN SYRINGE PUMP - MARATHI - 23MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:45</duration>
<date>2010-08-23</date>
<description><![CDATA[Medical technology produces a lot of waste. With two syringes -- one fat, other thin you can make a lovely pump. A steel ball dropped into the barrel of the thin syringe will make a good suction...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>QlUd1IeHoNQ</id>
<title><![CDATA[GO, NO-GO MATCHBOX - MARATHI - 25MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:50</duration>
<date>2010-08-23</date>
<description><![CDATA[This obedient matchbox can be made in just a few minutes. Stick a coin in a matchbox drawer to make it heavy. The thread in the drawer passes over a refill 'hillock'. When the thread is loose...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>yc_WDtgccyc</id>
<title><![CDATA[CYLINDER-CONE - MARATHI - 21MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:37</duration>
<date>2010-08-23</date>
<description><![CDATA[A cylinder with the same radius and height as that of a cone has three times more volume. Make a cone from a water proof tetrapak to fit snugly into a film can cylinder. Now fill the cone thrice...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>K-9TZIE9AB0</id>
<title><![CDATA[CIRCLING BIRD - MARATHI - 13MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>0:59</duration>
<date>2010-08-23</date>
<description><![CDATA[The circling bird is a readymade, but an innovative Chinese Toy. First you open the folded wings and then switch it on. This makes the bird flap its wings vigorously. Now hang the bird by a...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>ezxSFtE9kRQ</id>
<title><![CDATA[MAGNETIC MOTION - MARATHI - 18MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:21</duration>
<date>2010-08-23</date>
<description><![CDATA[This toy is a variation of an old traditional toy. A cycle spoke is mounted on a bottle stand. A plastic fan attached to the spoke spins under a ceiling fan. A ring magnet inserted in the spoke...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>H7sNEvIa2Rg</id>
<title><![CDATA[STRAW TURBINE - MARATHI - 24MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:54</duration>
<date>2010-08-20</date>
<description><![CDATA[The Straw Turbine is a simple spinning toy. A piece of stiff straw becomes the spinner. It is mounted on a wire axle with two loops which act as stoppers. The wire is connected to the end of...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>XADRbDY9tcg</id>
<title><![CDATA[MATCHSTICK MODELS -  MARATHI -  43MB]]></title>
<duration>4:39</duration>
<date>2010-08-20</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make these Matchstick Models with cycle valve tube, matchsticks and a long needle. Valve tube is a black rubber tube which is available even in remote villages. Two matchsticks go very snugly...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>hiTM4UBM_os</id>
<title><![CDATA[TALKING FROG - MARATHI - 31MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>2:45</duration>
<date>2010-08-20</date>
<description><![CDATA[The Talking Frog is a very dynamic paper toy and can be made with a paper square. The frog has a fixed jaw and a moving jaw which is operated by a stiff paper strip tucked in it. Make eyes...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>Hfn006vM1UQ</id>
<title><![CDATA[BLOW BALLOON WITH BOTTLE - MARATHI - 23MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:41</duration>
<date>2010-08-20</date>
<description><![CDATA[Normally you blow a balloon with your mouth. However it is great fun to blow a balloon inside a bottle. Make a small hole in the cylindrical surface near the base in a 2-litre bottle. Glue...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>9iX2XEuWtTY</id>
<title><![CDATA[PIPE PUMP - MARATHI - 25MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>2:11</duration>
<date>2010-08-20</date>
<description><![CDATA[With a 30-cm PVC pipe, cycle spoke, nut, rubber tube and other stuff you can make a very efficient pump. The pipe will be the cylinder. A few rubber tube washers are fixed to a bicycle spoke...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>SGSAzlgh2GI</id>
<title><![CDATA[FAN TAILED BIRD - MARATHI - 32MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>2:51</duration>
<date>2010-08-20</date>
<description><![CDATA[The Fan Tailed Bird is an extraordinary toy. This is essentially the well known Flapping Bird with a fan tail. The fan is a paper helicopter with a pin axle spinning inside a plastic ball pen...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>OKjgSWIiwaQ</id>
<title><![CDATA[PAPER PROTRACTOR - MARATHI - 32MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>2:29</duration>
<date>2010-08-20</date>
<description><![CDATA[Paper folding is essentially a geometry laboratory. With a square piece of paper you can fold a protractor with a dozen different angles. This is very empowering because you can fold it anywhere....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>tfoSkfzscIA</id>
<title><![CDATA[FLAPPING BIRD - MARATHI - 29MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>2:13</duration>
<date>2010-08-20</date>
<description><![CDATA[This marvelous Flapping Bird has been made by children in Japan for the last 300 years. This is also called as the Bird of Peace. All you need is a paper square and your ten little fingers...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>zPo0eU46R_8</id>
<title><![CDATA[GANDHI CAP - MARATHI - 27MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:55</duration>
<date>2010-08-20</date>
<description><![CDATA[With just half a newspaper you can fold India's National cap - also called the GANDHI cap. Many boys in rural areas still wear such a cap to school. This wonderful cap can be made bigger or...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>BpB22SBAtLs</id>
<title><![CDATA[BALLOON SPINNER - MARATHI - 10MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>0:50</duration>
<date>2010-08-20</date>
<description><![CDATA[Cut a bent straw such that both its legs are 10-cm long. Tie one end of the straw to the balloon with a rubber band. Inflate the balloon. Close the straw with your finger. As you release the...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>1uxFv4mzr_M</id>
<title><![CDATA[BOTTLE PLANTER - MARATHI - 21MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:35</duration>
<date>2010-08-20</date>
<description><![CDATA[Empty plastic bottles have become a great pollution menace. Recycle them to make a beautiful bottle planter. Make three bowls from old bottles and hang them with strong string. Fill these bowls...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>RyWaBnT3RqQ</id>
<title><![CDATA[BALLOON SPRINKLER - MARATHI - 21MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:34</duration>
<date>2010-08-20</date>
<description><![CDATA[Seal one end of the stiff straw with tape. Make four holes on this end. Fill a balloon with water. Tie the open end of the straw to the balloon with a rubber band. On releasing the mouth of...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>XFZe-5r8Gcw</id>
<title><![CDATA[NEWSPAPER ORIGAMI STORY - MARATHI - 32MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>2:32</duration>
<date>2010-08-20</date>
<description><![CDATA[This famous CAPTAIN'S HAT STORY is told while folding a newspaper. Fold a double newspaper and make several caps -- Umbrella cap, Fireman's cap, Shikari cap and a Policeman's cap. In the end...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>tUCDuydug8E</id>
<title><![CDATA[DANCING WASHERS - MARATHI - 19MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:24</duration>
<date>2010-08-20</date>
<description><![CDATA[You need is a very long threaded rod and some loose steel washers for this fun experiment. Fix the screw vertically on a wooden base. The washers should go freely in the screw. Place a washer...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>6GqSOmDp_oA</id>
<title><![CDATA[MAGNIFICENT MOTOR - MARATHI - 28MB]]></title>
<duration>2:01</duration>
<date>2010-08-20</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make this motor with a strong neodymium magnet, a 1.5-volt battery, and some flexi-wire. Stick a strong neodymium magnet to the base of a battery. Hang them from a pointed spoke. Now touch...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>h2jX42x49wo</id>
<title><![CDATA[SKELETAL BUTTERFLY - MARATHI - 20MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:31</duration>
<date>2010-08-18</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make this beautiful butterfly with strips of colored card sheet and glue. Shape and stick two strips to make a heart shape. This would be the main wing. Similarly, make another pair of wings....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>QKX8GxX38n0</id>
<title><![CDATA[MULTI-STORIES - MARATHI - 33MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>2:32</duration>
<date>2010-08-18</date>
<description><![CDATA[This model of this multi-storied apartment building is made with card sheet. Fan-fold and make corrugations in a card sheet. Cut lots of slits and then glue two ends to make a cylinder. Stand...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>o4eyBvbmapo</id>
<title><![CDATA[PECKING BIRDS - MARATHI - 25MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:50</duration>
<date>2010-08-18</date>
<description><![CDATA[This traditional toy can be easily made with simple materials. The toy is essentially a rectangular frame made of stiff straws. All the four corners are 'hinged'. They move and readily transform...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>hqLqttphsn8</id>
<title><![CDATA[NO GLUE BAG - MARATHI - 23MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:41</duration>
<date>2010-08-18</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make a useful paper bag using an old A-4 size Xerox sheet. This nice thing about this bag is that it requires no glue or staples. Fold the open ends. Cut slits and fold flaps on opposite sides....]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>TDlQmzkLFRE</id>
<title><![CDATA[FLYING FISH - MARATHI - 16MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:12</duration>
<date>2010-08-18</date>
<description><![CDATA[The Flying Fish is perhaps the simplest flying object ever. Make two half-cuts on a thin strip of paper and then interlock them into a fish shape. When you throw this fish up in the air it...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>2m38_ZoU8bw</id>
<title><![CDATA[NEWSPAPER BIN - MARATHI - 19MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:22</duration>
<date>2010-08-18</date>
<description><![CDATA[Make a waste paper basket or a bin from an old newspaper. You will need a double spread newspaper. With a few simple folds you will be able to make a paper box with a square base. This bin...]]></description>
</entry>

<entry>
<id>2pj_-O-gb84</id>
<title><![CDATA[MANGO SEED ANIMAL - MARATHI - 23MB.wmv]]></title>
<duration>1:41</duration>
<date>2010-08-18</date>
<description><![CDATA[After eating the mango don't throw away its seed -- for you can make a beautiful animal out of it. Make six holes in the mango seed -- four for the legs and one each for the eye and the tail....]]></description>
</entry>

</feed>
